<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="ata">
        <item>ALL-STAR SQUADRON\nKeyword(s): All-Star Squadron\nCost:
			2\nCharacters using this team ability modify their attack value by +1
			when making
			a close combat attack against a character at least twice
			its point
			value.
			\n\n
			Los personajes usando este ATA 
			modiﬁcan su valor de ataque en +1 
			cuando hacen un ataque cuerpo a 
			cuerpo contra un personaje de al 
			menos el doble de su valor de 
			puntos.</item>
        <item>ALPHA FLIGHT\nKeyword(s): Alpha Flight\nCost: 4\nOnce during
			each game, choose any team ability or opposing character.
			Each
			friendly character using this team ability modifies its attack
			value
			by +1 when attacking the chosen character or a character
			possessing
			the chosen team ability.
			\n\n
            Cada vez que un personaje usando 
			este ATA sufre 2 o más daños por un 
			ataque del oponente, coloca un 
			contador de Hermandad en esta 
			carta. Antes de realizar una acción no 
			gratuita, una ﬁgura aliada que use 
			este ATA puede retirar cualquier 
			número de contadores de Hermandad 
			para añadir +1 a su movimiento, 
			ataque o rango, hasta ﬁnal de acción.</item>
        <item>AMAZON\nKeyword(s): Amazon\nCost: 4\nWhenever a character using
			this team ability takes 2 or more damage from an
			opponent\'s attack,
			put a Sisterhood token on this card. Before being
			given a non-free
			action, a friendly character using this team ability
			may remove any
			number of Sisterhood tokens from this card. Modify
			that character\'s
			speed, attack, or range value by +1 for each token
			removed until that
			action is resolved.
			\n\n
            Cada vez que un personaje usando 
			este ATA sufre 2 o más daños por un 
			ataque del oponente, coloca un 
			contador de Hermandad en esta 
			carta. Antes de realizar una acción no 
			gratuita, una ﬁgura aliada que use 
			este ATA puede retirar cualquier 
			número de contadores de Hermandad 
			para añadir +1 a su movimiento, 
			ataque o rango, hasta ﬁnal de acción.</item>
        <item>ANIMAL\n
		    Keyword(s): Animal\n
		    Cost: 4\n
		    At the beginning of your turn, roll a d6. On a result of 5-6 all friendly characters using this team ability ignore Shape Change and Stealth this turn.</item>
        <item>ANNIHILATORS\nKeyword(s): Annihilators\nCost: 4\n
			When a character using this team ability KO\'s an opposing character of a higher point value with an attack, remove an action token from each friendly character using this team ability that\'s less points than the KO\'d character.
			\n\n
			Cuando un personaje usando este 
			ATA hace KO (con un ataque) a un 
			personaje opuesto de mayor 
			puntuación, rera un contador de 
			acción de cada ﬁgura aliada usando 
			este ATA que sea de menor puntuación 
			que la ﬁgura KO.</item>
        <item>ARKHAM ASYLUM\n
    Keyword(s): Arkham Asylum\n
    Cost: 4
    At the beginning of your turn, roll a d6 for all friendly characters using this team ability. Those characters can use the indicated power until your next turn. Uncopyable. 
    1–2 Plasticity
    3–4 Leap/Climb
    5–6 Phasing/Teleport</item>
        <item>ASGARDIAN\n
		    Keyword(s): Asgardian\n
			Cost: 5\n
			A character using this team ability can\'t have its Willpower or Indomitable countered. A character using this team ability can use Willpower on its first click.
			\n\n
			A un personaje utilizando esta 
			habilidad de equipo no se le puede 
			cancelar ni Fuerza de Voluntad ni 
			Indominable.
			Un personaje usando esta habilidad 
			de equipo puede usar Fuerza de 
			Voluntad en su primer click.</item>
        <item>ATLANTIS\nKeyword(s): Atlantis\nCost: 2\nWhenever a character
			using this team ability occupies water terrain, modify
			its defense
			value by +1 against ranged combat attacks.
			\n\n
            Cada vez que un personaje usando 
			este ATA ocupa terreno acuático, 
			modiﬁca su valor de defensa en +1 
			contra ataques a distancia.</item>
        <item>AVENGERS (HEROIC AGE)\n
			Keyword(s): Avengers\n
			Cost: 2\n
			When a character using this team ability is given a move action, after actions resolve roll a d6 that can’t be rerolled. On a roll of 6, remove an action token from that character.
			\n\n
			Cuando a un personaje usando este 
			ATA se le da una acción de movimiento, 
			después de que se resuelva tira 
			1d6 que no puede ser repetido. En 
			un resultado de 6, retira un contador 
			de acción de ese personaje.</item>
        <item>AVENGERS RESPONSE UNIT\n
			Keyword(s): Avengers\n
			Cost: 3\n
			When one or more characters using this team ability is adjacent to a friendly character making a close combat attack, modify the characters attack value by +1.
			\n\n
			Cuando uno o más personajes 
			usando esta habilidad de equipo se 
			encuentre adyacente a un personaje 
			aliado haciendo un ataque cuerpo a 
			cuerpo, modiﬁca el valor de ataque 
			del personaje en +1.</item>
        <item>BATMAN FAMILY\n
    Keyword(s): Batman Family\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Characters using this team ability within 8 squares of a friendly
    character named "Batman" or "Bruce Wayne" can use Willpower.
    When not within 8 squares of a friendly character named
    "Batman" or "Bruce Wayne", characters using this team ability
    modify their speed and range values by +1.</item>
        <item>BATMAN INC\n
    Keyword(s): Batman Inc\n
    Cost: 3\n
    At the beginning of the game, choose an opposing character for all
    characters using this team ability. While any character using this
    team ability is on the map, whenever the sum of all modifiers
    applied to that opposing character\'s combat values is greater than
    +1, the sum of all modifiers is instead +1.</item>
        <item>BIRDS OF PREY\n
    Keyword(s): Birds of Prey\n
    Cost: 1\n
    Once per turn, one friendly character using this team ability can
    use Support as a free action. When it does, it may only target a
    character with whom it shares a keyword and it subtracts 3 from
    the d6 roll instead of 2.</item>
        <item>BLACK LANTERN CORPS\n
       Cost: 1\n
       Keyword(s): Black Lantern Corps\n
       When a character using this
                  team ability uses Regeneration, its minimum result is 1.\n
                 Uncopyable</item>
        <item>CHECKMATE\nKeyword(s): Checkmate\nCost: 6\nMinion: Kings and
			Queens and Bishops\nWhen another friendly character using
			this team
			ability and with a point value greater than 50 is within 8
			squares,
			this character can be given a power action to use Perplex if
			it can\'t
			already use Perplex.
			\n\nSiervos: Reyes, reinas y alfiles\n
            Cuando otra ﬁgura aliada usando 
			este ATA y con valor en puntos por 
			encima de 50 está a 8 casillas, este 
			personaje puede realizar una acción 
			de poder para usar Perplex si no 
			podía ulizarlo previamente.</item>
        <item>DARK AVENGERS\nKeyword(s): Dark Avengers\nCost: 4\nWhenever an
			opposing character takes damage from an attack by a character
			using
			this team ability, modify that opposing character\'s defense
			value by
			-1 until the end of the turn. Each opposing character can\'t
			have this
			modifier applied more than once per turn.
			\n\n
            Cada vez que una ﬁgura opuesta 
			reciba daño de un ataque de un 
			personaje usando este ATA, modiﬁca 
			el valor de defensa de la ﬁgura 
			opuesta en -1 hasta el ﬁnal del 
			turno. Cada personaje opuesto no 
			puede tener este modiﬁcador 
			aplicado más de una vez por turno.</item>
        <item>DEFENDERS\n
    Keyword(s): Defenders\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Characters using this team ability may replace their attack value
    with the unmodified attack value of an adjacent friendly character
    using this team ability.</item>
        <item>ELDERS OF THE UNIVERSE\n
			Keyword(s):Elders of the Universe\n
			Cost: 5\n
			Opposing characters can’t attempt a relic roll while at least two friendly characters can use this team ability.
			\n\n
			Los personajes opuestos no pueden 
			intentar hacer una tirada para 
			conseguir una reliquia mientras al 
			menos dos personajes aliados usen 
			esta habilidad de equipo.</item>
        <item>FANTASTIC FORCE\nKeyword(s): Fantastic Four\nCost: 5\nCharacters
			using this team ability may replace their defense value with the
			unmodified defense value of an adjacent friendly character using this
			team ability.
			\n\n
            Los personajes usando esta ATA 
			pueden reemplazar su valor de 
			defensa con el valor de defensa sin 
			modiﬁcar de un personaje aliado 
			adyacente que esté usando también 
			esta ATA.
			\n\n
			Cuando un personaje usando este 
			ATA hace KO a un personaje enemigo, 
			ese personaje puede curar 1 daño a 
			cualquier personaje usando este ATA.</item>
        <item>FEARSOME FIVE\n
    Keyword(s): Fearsome Five\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Characters using this team ability can use Mastermind, but may
    only transfer damage to friendly characters using this team ability.
    Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>FF\n
			Keyword(s): Fantastic Four\n
			Cost: 3\n
			When a character using this team ability KO’s an opposing character, that character may heal any character using this team ability of 1 damage.</item>
        <item>FLASHPOINT\n
			Keyword(s): Flashpoint\n
			Cost: 4\n
			Once per game per character using this team ability, it may use Probability Control during an adjacent friendly character\'s attack. When they do, you may reroll only one die and keep the other. Uncopyable.
			\n\n
			Una vez por juego y por personaje 
			usando este ATA, puede usar Control 
			de Probabilidad durante el ataque 
			de una ﬁgura aliada adyacente. 
			Cuando lo hace, puede repetir 
			unicamente un dado y mantener el 
			otro. ATA no copiable.</item>
        <item>GCPD\n
    Keyword(s): Gotham City and Police (both keywords)\n
    Cost: 2\n
    At the beginning of your turn, characters using this team ability
    that have no action tokens may be given a move action as a free
    action, with a speed value of 4.</item>
        <item>GEN13\n
    Keyword(s): Gen13\n
    At the beginning of the game, choose a keyword for all characters
    using this team ability. All opposing characters with that keyword
    modify their attack value by -1 when a character using this team
    ability is targeted.</item>
        <item>GREAT LAKES AVENGERS\nKeyword(s): Great Lakes Avengers\nCost: 3\n
			During an attack made by a character using this team ability,
			opposing characters cannot use Probability Control unless a
			friendly character has already used Probability Control during
			this attack. Uncopyable.
			\n\n
			Durante un ataque hecho por un 
			personaje usando este ATA, los 
			personajes opuestos no pueden usar 
			Control de Probabilidad a menos que 
			una ﬁgura aliada lo haya utilizado 
			durante este ataque. No puede ser 
			usada por comodines.</item>
        <item>GREEN LANTERN HONOR GUARD\nKeyword(s): Green Lantern
			Corps\nCost: 5\nWhenever a character using this team ability attacks,
			modify their attack
			value by +1 for each other friendly character that
			attacked the same
			target this turn while using this team ability.
			\n\n
			Cuando un personaje usando este 
			ATA realiza un ataque, modiﬁca su 
			valor de ATK en +1 por cada otra 
			ﬁgura aliada que haya atacado al 
			mismo objetivo este turno, que 
			también estuviera usando este ATA.</item>
        <item>GUARDIANS OF THE GALAXY\nKeyword(s): Guardians of the
			Galaxy\nCost: 4\nPowers possessed by characters using this team
			ability can\'t be countered.
			This team ability can\'t be used by wild
			cards.
			\n\n
			Los poderes poseídos por los personajes 
			que utilicen este ATA no 
			pueden ser cancelados. Esta ATA no 
			puede ser usada por comodines.</item>
        <item>GUARDIANS OF THE GALAXY (SILVER AGE)\nKeyword(s): Guardians of the Galaxy\nCost: 1\nCharacters using this team ability are wild cards, but don\'t possess any other team abilities. Uncopyable.
            \n\n
            Los personajes usando este ATA se 
			consideran comodines, pero no 
			poseen ningún otra habilidad de 
			equipo. No copiable.</item>
        <item>THE HAND\n
			Keyword(s): The Hand\n
			Cost: 7\n
			When it is not your turn, lines of fire to a character using this team ability are blocked if this character is adjacent to a wall or blocking terrain.
			\n\n
			Fuera de tu turno, las lineas de visión 
			marcadas a un personaje usando 
			este ATA se consideran bloqueadas si 
			se encuentra adyacente a un muro o 
			a terreno bloqueado.</item>
        <item>HELLIONS\nKeyword(s): Hellions\nCost: 5\nWhen a friendly
			character using this team ability is KO\'d during an
			opponent\'s turn,
			remove an action token from another friendly
			character with higher
			point value that\'s using this team ability.
			\n\n
            Cuando un personaje aliado usando 
			este ATA es KO durante el turno del 
			oponente, retira un contador de 
			acción de otro personaje aliado con 
			mayor puntuación y que esté 
			utilizando este ATA.</item>
        <item>HEROES FOR HIRE\n
    Keyword(s): Heroes for Hire\n
    Cost: 8\n
    At the beginning of the game, place a number of HIRED tokens on
    this card equal to the number of characters using this team ability.
    Once per turn, you may remove a HIRED token from this card and
    give a character using this team ability one action as a free action.
    Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>HORSEMEN OF APOCALYPSE\nKeyword(s): Horsemen of
			Apocalypse\nCost: 1\nAs long as you control exactly 4 characters
			using this team ability,
			modify this character\'s attack value by +1.
			Uncopyable.
			\n\n
			Siempre y cuando controles cuatro 
			personajes usando este ATA, 
			modiﬁca el valor de ataque de este 
			personaje en +1. No puede ser 
			usada por Comodines.</item>
        <item>HOWLING COMMANDOS\n
			Keyword(s): Howling Commandos\n
			Cost: 3\n
			Friendly characters can use Support if they can\'t already, but only to target a character using this team ability that took 2 or more damage from a single opponent’s attack since your last turn.
			\n\n
			Los personajes aliados pueden usar 
			Soporte si no lo tenían ya, pero 
			solamente para hacer objetivo a un 
			personaje que tenga esta ATA y que 
			haya recibido 2 o más daños de un 
			único ataque enemigo desde tu 
			último turno.</item>
        <item>HULKBUSTERS\n
    		Keyword(s): Hulkbusters\n
    		Cost: 2\n
    		When there are more friendly characters using this team ability on the map than the total number of opposing characters, and a character using this team ability targets an opposing character with a higher point value, modify that opposing character\'s defense value by -1 for this attack.
    		\n\n
    		Cuando haya más personajes aliados 
			usando este ATA en el mapa que el 
			total de ﬁguras opuestas, y un 
			personaje usando este ATA esté 
			haciendo objetivo a un personaje 
			opuesto de mayor puntuación, 
			modiﬁca el valor de defensa del 
			objetivo en -1 para este ataque.</item>
        <item>HULKED-OUT HEROES\n
   			Keyword(s): Hulked-Out Heroes\n
    		Cost: 5\n
    		Characters using this team ability can use Super Strength if they are not on click #1. Uncopyable.
    		\n\n
    		Los personajes usando este ATA 
			pueden usar Super Fuerza si no 
			están en el click #1. No puede ser 
			usado por comodines.</item>
        <item>HYDRA DEEP SCIENCE DIVISION\n
			Cost: 3\n
			Keyword(s): HYDRA\n
			When an opposing character uses Outwit, Perplex, or Probability 
    Control, modify its range value by -1 for each friendly character 
    using this team ability. Reduce the minimum range value by the 
    same amount, but no lower than 1.
			\n\n</item>
        <item>INFINITY WATCH\n
            Keyword(s): Infinity Watch\n
            Cost: 2\n
			When a character using this team ability rolls for a relic with the #relic# set symbol, it succeeds on a roll of 3-6. Uncopyable.
			\n\n
            Cuando un personaje usando este 
			ATA tira el dado para coger una 
			reliquia con símbolo #relic#, tiene 
			éxito con una tirada de 3-6. No 
			copiable.</item>
        <item>INHUMANS\n
			Keyword(s): Inhumans\n
			Cost: 4\n
			Characters using this team ability may use the Carry ability, but only to carry characters that can also use this team ability, and may carry those characters regardless of their combat symbols. Uncopyable.
			\n\n
			Los personajes usando este ATA 
			pueden usar la habilidad de transporte, 
			pero solo para llevar personajes 
			que también usen este ATA, 
			pudiendo llevarlos sin importar sus 
			símbolos de combate. No copiable.</item>
        <item>INTELLIGENCIA\n
    		Keyword(s): Intelligencia \n
    		Cost: 3 \n
		    If no friendly character is affected by an opponent\'s Outwit and/or Perplex, friendly characters that can use Outwit and/or Perplex may use them to target characters within 12 squares instead of 10 squares and all characters using this team ability modify their range values by +2.
		    \n\n
		    Si ningún personaje aliado está 
			afectado por Outwit y/o Perplex del 
			enemigo, los personajes aliados que 
			puedan usar Outwit y/o Perplex 
			pueden hacerlo a 12 casillas en lugar 
			de 10 y todos los personajes usando 
			este ATA modiﬁcan su valor de rango 
			en +2.</item>
        <item>JUSTICE LEAGUE\n
    Keyword(s): Justice League\n
    Cost: 1\n
    A character using this team ability modifies its defense value by +1
    when attacked by a character possessing
    #flight#, #sharpshooter#, #indomitable#, or #giant# combat symbols.</item>
        <item>JUSTICE LEAGUE (SILVER AGE)\n
   		 	Keyword(s): JLA, Justice League, Justice League of America \n
    		Cost: 4 \n
    		Once during each game, choose any team ability or opposing character. Each friendly character using this team ability modifies its attack value by +1 when attacking the chosen character or a character possessing the chosen team ability.
    		\n\n
    		Una vez por juego, elige una habilidad 
			de equipo o ﬁgura oponente. 
			Cada personaje aliado usando este 
			ATA modiﬁca su valor de ataque en 
			+1 cuando ataca al personaje elegido 
			o uno que posea la habilidad de 
			equipo escogida.</item>
        <item>JUSTICE LEAGUE: GENERATION LOST\n
    Keyword(s): Justice League International\n
    Cost: 3\n
    At the beginning of the game, choose an opposing character for all
    characters using this team ability. Characters using this team
    ability ignore hindering terrain when drawing a line of fire to that
    character.</item>
        <item>JUSTICE LEAGUE: NEW 52\n
		    Keyword(s): Justice League\n
		    Cost: 3\n
		    When a character using this team ability is adjacent to a friendly character using Leadership, add 1 to the result of the die rill, maximum 6, if not already modified by this effect.</item>
        <item>JUSTICE LEAGUE DARK\n
		    Keyword(s): Justice League\n
		    Cost: 2\n
		    When a character using this team ability is adjacent to a friendly character using this team ability, opposing characters modify their range values by -2 if not already modified by this effect. Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>JUSTICE LEAGUE INTERNATIONAL\n
            Keyword(s): Justice League Antarctica, Justice League Europe, or Justice League	International\n
			Cost: 3\n
			Whenever a character using this team ability
			would be dealt damage, you can
			choose to reduce damage dealt by 1 if
			you deal 1 unavoidable damage
			to a friendly character using this team
			ability that is adjacent to
			this character. (This can only be used
			once per damage dealt).
			\n\n
			Cada vez que un personaje usando 
			este ATA fuera a recibir daño, puedes 
			elegir reducir el daño hecho en 1 si 
			haces 1 daño inevitable a una ﬁgura 
			aliada que use este ATA y esté 
			adyacente a este personaje  (Sólo 
			puede ser usado una vez por daño 
			sufrido).</item>
        <item>KRYPTONIAN\n
    		Keyword(s): Kryptonian \n
   			Cost: 2 \n
    		When characters using this team ability occupy the highest level of clear, outdoor terrain and is not adjacent to blocking or hindering terrain, modify their attack values by +1.
    		\n\n
    		Cuando personajes usando este ATA 
			ocupan una casilla de terreno 
			exterior, no adyacente a terreno 
			bloqueante u obstaculizado, en la 
			más alta posición del mapa, modiﬁca 
			sus valores de ataque en +1</item>
        <item>LEAGUE OF ASSASSINS\n
            Keyword(s): League of Assassins\n
            Cost: 7\n
            When it is not your turn, lines of fire to a character using this team ability are blocked
			if this
			character is adjacent to a wall or blocking terrain.
			\n\n
            Las lineas de visión hacía una ﬁgura 
			usando este ATA se consideran 
			bloqueadas si el personaje se 
			encuentra adyacente a un muro o 
			terreno bloqueante.</item>
        <item>LEGION LOST\n
			Keyword(s): Legion of Super Heroes, Legion of Super Villains \n
			Cost: 4 \n
			Once at the beginning of the game, if no character on your force possesses a team ability that isn\'t a wild card team ability, choose any one DC team ability other than an additional team ability, a wild card team ability, or a team ability that can\'t be used by wild cards. Characters using this team ability are not wild cards and can use the chosen team ability if they can\'t already.
			\n\n
			Al comienzo del juego, si ninguna ﬁgura 
			de tu equipo posee una habilidad de 
			equipo que no sea comodín, elige una 
			habilidad de equipo de DC (excepto 
			comodín, ATAs o habilidades no 
			copiables). Los personajes usando este 
			ATA no son comodines y pueden usar la 
			habilidad elegida si no podían hacerlo 
			previamente.</item>
        <item>LEGION OF MONSTERS\n
    Keyword(s): Legion of Monsters\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Characters using this team ability can use Plasticity unless
    adjacent to an opposing character with the Legion of Monsters or
    Monster keyword.</item>
        <item>LEGIONNAIRES\n
            Keyword(s): Legion of Super Heroes\n
            Cost: 2\n
            Whenever the friendly character with the highest point value
			that\'s using
			this team ability is KO\'d, remove one action token from
			each other
			friendly character using this team ability.
			\n\n
            Cada vez que una ﬁgura aliada con 
			mayor puntos que la ﬁgura que usa 
			este ATA sea KO, retira un contador 
			de acción de cada otra ﬁgura aliada 
			que use este ATA.</item>
        <item>MARVEL KNIGHTS\n
		    Keyword(s): Marvel Knights \n
		    Cost: 10 \n
		    Characters using this team ability can use Stealth.
		    \n\n
		    Los personajes usando este ATA 
			pueden usar Sigilo.</item>
        <item>MAXIMUM CARNAGE\n
    Keyword(s): Maximum Carnage\n
    Cost: 4\n
    When a single opposing character takes damage from an attack by
    a character using this team ability, after actions resolve, choose
    another opposing character adjacent to the first. That other
    character is dealt damage equal to the amount of damage taken.
    Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>MIDNIGHT SONS\n
    Keyword(s): Midnight Sons\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Characters using this team ability can use Stealth on their starting 
    click. If that character can already use Stealth on their starting click, lines of fire may not be drawn to that character by opposing
    characters while on that click.</item>
        <item>THE MIGHTY\n
		    Keyword(s): The Mighty\n
		    Cost: 1\n
		    When a character using this team ability hits an opposing character and the attack roll is double, 
		    place 1 Mighty token on this card for each 100 points of game\'s build total. Before any attack roll
		    , you may remove one Mighty token from this card and modify the attacking character\'s attack value 
		    by -1 for this attack.\n\n
		    A character using this team ability modifies their attack value by +1 when attacking a character 
		    using The Worthy additional team ability or posessing The Worthy keyword.</item>
        <item>MIGHTY AVENGERS\n
			Keyword(s): Avengers\n
			Cost: 4\n
			When a character using this team ability destroys a square of blocking terrain, roll a d6 after actions resolve. On a roll of 5, you may place a standard light object in that square. On a roll of 6, you may place a standard heavy object in that square.
			\n\n
			Cuando un personaje usando esta 
			ATA destruye una casilla de terreno 
			bloqueante, tira 1d6 después de que 
			se resuelva la acción. En un resultado 
			de 5, puedes colocar un objeto ligero 
			en esa casilla. En un resultado de 6, 
			puedes colocar un objeto pesado en 
			esa casilla.</item>
        <item>THE MOB\n
    Keyword(s): Gotham City Underworld\n
    Cost: 2
    The highest point friendly character using this team ability can use
    Mastermind, but may only transfer damage to a friendly character
    using this team ability.</item>
        <item>MODOK\'S 11\n
			Keyword(s): MODOK’s 11\n
			Cost: 2\n
			Give a character using this team ability a free action to remove
			one object from the game. This object must be a light or heavy
			object in the character’s square or a square adjacent to the
			character.
			\n\n
			Dale una acción gratuita a un personaje 
			usando este ATA para retirar un 
			objeto del juego. Este objeto debe 
			ser ligero o pesado y estar en la 
			casilla del personaje o adyacente a él.</item>
        <item>MONSTER SOCIETY OF EVIL\nKeyword(s): Injustice Society or
			Monster Society of Evil\n
			Cost: 5\nAt the end of your turn, you may
			roll a d6 for each friendly character
			using this team ability. On a
			result of 5 or 6, deal 1 damage to each
			opposing character adjacent to
			that character that hasn\'t already
			been dealt damage by this team
			ability this turn.
			\n\n
			Al ﬁnal de tu turno, puedes tirar 1d6 
			por cada ﬁgura aliada que use este 
			ATA. En un resultado de 5-6, haz 1 
			daño a cada ﬁgura oponente que 
			esté adyacente a este personaje y 
			que no haya recibido daño por este 
			ATA durante este turno.</item>
        <item>MORLOCKS\nKeyword(s): Gene Nation or Morlocks\nCost: 2* (0 if
			the character possesses the Morlocks team symbol)\nWhenever a
			character using this team ability makes a close combat
			attack, modify
			its attack value by +1 for each other character using
			this team
			ability adjacent to both this character and the target.
			\n\n
			Cada vez que un personaje que use 
			este ATA haga un ataque cuerpo a 
			cuerpo, modiﬁca su valor de ataque 
			en +1 por cada otro personaje 
			usando este ATA que esté adyacente 
			tanto al atacante como a su objetivo.\n\n
			* El ATA cuesta 0 si la ﬁgura posee el 
			símbolo de equipo Morlock</item>
        <item>N.O.W.H.E.R.E.\n
    Keyword(s): N.O.W.H.E.R.E.\n
    Cost: 2\n
    Characters using this team ability that have no action tokens can use #impmov# #ignht#, #ignbt# during move actions.</item>
        <item>NEGATIVE ZONE\nKeyword(s): Negative Zone\nCost: 2\n
			A character using this team ability may ignore one wall or square of blocking terrain for movement purposes when it uses Charge or Running Shot. If it does and misses all target opposing characters deal this character 1 unavoidable damage after actions resolve.
			\n\n
			Un personaje usando este ATA 
			puede ignorar un muro o casilla de 
			terreno bloqueado a efectos de 
			movimiento cuando use Carga o 
			Disparo a la carrera. Si lo hace y falla 
			el ataque, el personaje recibe 1 daño 
			inevitable después de resolver la 
			acción.</item>
        <item>NEW MUTANTS\nKeyword(s): Generation X, New Mutants\nCost: 4\n
			Whenever a character using this team ability would be dealt damage,
			you may
			give an action token to an adjacent friendly character using
			this
			team ability. If you do, deal all of the damage to that character
			instead.
			\n\n
			Cada vez que un personaje usando 
			este ATA fuera a recibir daño, 
			puedes poner un contador de acción 
			en una ﬁgura aliada adyacente que 
			use este ATA. Si lo hace, haz todo el 
			daño a dicha ﬁgura en lugar de a la 
			que fuera a recibir el daño.</item>
        <item>NEW TEEN TITANS\n
    Keyword(s): Teen Titans\n
    Cost: 3\n
    The highest-point friendly character using this team ability can use 
    Leadership, but may only remove action tokens from friendly 
    characters using this team ability.</item>
        <item>NEWER FANTASTIC FOUR\nKeyword(s): Fantastic Four\nCost: 1\n
			A character using this team ability modifies its attack value by +1 when attacking characters possessing #indomitable#, #giant#, or #colossus#.
			\n\n
			Un personaje usando este ATA 
			modiﬁca su valor de ataque en +1 
			cuando ataca a ﬁguras que posean 
			alguno de estos símbolos: #indomitable#, #giant#, or #colossus#.</item>
        <item>NEXTWAVE\nKeyword(s): Nextwave\nCost 5\nWhen a character using
			this team ability KO\'s an opposing character of a
			higher point value
			with an attack, place this character anywhere on
			the map.
			\n\n
            Cuando un personaje usando este 
			ATA hace KO a una ﬁgura opuesta de 
			mayor puntuación con un ataque, 
			coloca a este personaje en cualquier 
			lugar del mapa.</item>
        <item>NOVA CORPS\nKeyword(s): Nova Corps\nCost: -10*\n
			Friendly characters ignore traits named \"Share Through the Worldmind\" possessed by friendly characters. *(0 if the character dosen\'t possess the trait named \"Share Through the Worldmind.\")
			\n\n
			Los personajes aliados ignoran las 
			habilidades llamadas “Vínculados a 
			través del mundo mente” poseidas 
			por otros personajes aliados.\n\n
			*0 si el personaje no posee la habilidad 
			llamada “Vinculado a través del mundo 
			mente”.</item>
        <item>OFFENDERS\n
    Keyword(s): Offenders\n
    Cost: 4\n
    When a character using this team ability attacks a single
    character, replace that character\'s defense value with the lowest
    printed defense value among all characters adjacent to that
    character. Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>THE ORDER\nKeyword(s): Defenders\nCost: 3\n
			Character using this team ability cannot be targeted by an opposing character using one of the listed powers if any character using this team ability was already hit by an opposing character using that power this turn.\n
			Flurry				Incapacitate\n
			Charge				Penetrating/Psychic Blast\n
			Hypersonic Speed	Ranged Combat Expert\n
			Running Shot		Exploit Weakness\n
			Blades/Claws/Fangs	Close Combat Expert
			\n\n
			Los personajes usando este ATA no pueden ser 
			objetivos de ﬁguras oponentes que usen 
			algunos de los siguientes poderes si cualquier 
			ﬁgura usando este ATA fue impactada por una 
			ﬁgura oponente usando ese poder durante 
			este turno.\n\n
			Flurry · Incapacitar \n 
			Carga · Golpe Psíquico \n 
			Velocidad hipersónica · Experto en combate a distancia \n
			Disparo a la carrera · Explotar debilidad \n
			Garras · Experto en combate cuerpo a cuerpo.</item>
        <item>ORIGINAL SINISTER SIX\n
    Keyword(s): Sinister Syndicate\n
    Cost: 3\n
    When a character using this team ability hits an opposing
    character, mark that character with a Sinister Six token. When a
    character using this team ability attacks an opposing character
    marked with one or more Sinister Six tokens, modify their attack
    value by +1 for each token.
    When attacking a single target with one or more Sinister Six tokens,
    if the target\'s name Spider-Man or possesses the Spider-Man
    Family keyword or the Spider-Man symbol, modify this character\'s damage 
    value by +1.</item>
        <item>OUTLAWS\nKeyword(s): Outlaws\nCost: 1\nWhen a character using
			this team ability is given a move action, modify
			that character\'s
			speed values by +1 for each adjacent character using
			this team ability
			at the beginning of the move action.
			\n\n
            Cada vez que un personaje usando 
			este ATA realiza una acción de 
			movimiento, modiﬁca el valor de 
			velocidad en +1 por cada ﬁgura 
			adyacente que este usando esta ATA 
			al comienzo de la acción.</item>
        <item>OUTSIDERS\n
    Keyword(s): Outsiders
    Cost: 3\n
    At the beginning of your turn, roll a d6 for all friendly characters
    using this team ability. If the result is equal to or less than the
    number of friendly characters that can use this team ability, you
    may immediately give one of those characters a close combat
    attack as a free action, using its printed combat values.
    Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>PHANTOM ZONE\n
			    Keyword(s): Phantom Zone\n
			    Cost: 4\nOnce per game per character using this team ability, when they would take 4 or more damage from an attack, you may roll a d6. On a result of 4-6, ignore the damage and place this character in your starting area.
			    \n\n
			Una vez por juego y por ﬁgura 
			usando este ATA, cuando reciba 4 o 
			más daños de un ataque, puedes 
			tirar 1d6. En un resultado de 4-6, 
			ignora el daño y coloca este personaje 
			en tu área de inicio.</item>
        <item>PRIME\'S TITANS\n
    Keyword(s): Prime\'s Titans\n
    Cost: 6\n
    When a character using this team ability KO’s an opposing
    character, remove an action token from each other friendly
    character using this team ability. Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>RAVAGERS\n
    Keyword(s): Ravagers\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Characters using this team ability automatically break away.
    Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>REAVERS\nKeyword(s): Reavers\nCost: 8\nWhen a character using
			this team ability has two action tokens, it can be
			given a non-free
			action. If you do, after actions resolve deal the
			character 1
			unavoidable damage and do not clear action tokens from it
			at the end
			of the turn.
			\n\n
            Cuando un personaje utilizando este 
			ATA tiene dos contadores de acción, 
			puede realizar una acción no 
			gratuita. Si lo hace, tras resolver la 
			acción hazle 1 daño inevitable y no 
			retires los contadores de acción al 
			ﬁnal del turno.</item>
        <item>RED HOOD AND THE OUTLAWS\n
    Keyword(s): Outlaws\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Opposing characters with the highest point value on their force 
    can\'t draw lines of fire to characters using this team ability. 
    Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>ROGUES\n
			    Keyword(s): Rogues \n
			    Cost: 6 \n
			    Characters using this team ability can use Outwit, but only to counter Hypersonic Speed, the Move and Attack ability, or a special power that specifically allows that character to use Hypersonic Speed or the Move and Attack ability. Uncopyable.
			    \n\n
			Los personajes usando este ATA 
			pueden usar Outwit, pero solamente 
			para cancelar Velocidad Hipersónica, 
			Mover y Atacar o un poder especial 
			que permita usar alguno de estos 
			dos poderes. Este ATA no puede ser 
			copiada.</item>
        <item>RUNAWAYS\nKeyword(s): Runaways\nCost: 3\nWhenever a character
			using this team ability attacks, modify their attack
			value by +1 for
			each other friendly character that dealt damage to an
			opposing
			character this turn while using this team ability.
			\n\n
            Cada vez que un personaje que use 
			este ATA ataque, modiﬁca su valor 
			de ataque en +1 por cada otro 
			personaje aliado que haya dañado a 
			un personaje opuesto este turno 
			que estuviera usando este ATA.</item>
        <item>SAVAGE LAND\n
			    Keyword(s): Savage Land\n
			    Cost: 3\n
			    Once per game per character using this team ability, when they roll a d6 for Blades/Claws/Fangs, if the result is a 1 that character may reroll the d6.
			    \n\n
			Una vez por juego y por personaje 
			usando este ATA, cuando tire 1d6 a 
			causa de Cuchillo/Garras/Colmillos, 
			si es resultado es 1 puede volver a 
			tirar el dado.</item>
        <item>SECRET AVENGERS\n
			Keyword(s): Avengers\n
			Cost: 5\n
			Characters using this team ability can’t be the target of an opponent’s Outwit or Perplex unless they’ve been targeted with an attack previously in the same turn.
			\n\n
			Los personajes usando este ATA no 
			pueden ser objetivo de Outwit o 
			Perplex del oponente amenos que 
			hayan sido objetivos de un ataque 
			anteriormente en el mismo turno.</item>
        <item>SECRET INVASION\n
        Cost: 2\n
Keyword(s): Skrulls\n
When a character using this team ability is targeted with an attack
by an opposing character with which it shares a keyword, modify
this character’s defense value by +1.</item>
        <item>SECRET SIX\nKeyword(s): Secret Six\nCost: 3\nWhenever a
			character using this team ability is KO\'d, you may roll a d6 and
			subtract 2 (minimum 1). Deal that much damage, divided as you choose,
			among any number of opposing characters adjacent to the square the
			KO\'d character occupied.
			\n\n
            Cada vez que un personaje usando 
			este ATA es KO, puedes tirar 1d6 y 
			restar 2 (mínimo 1). Haz esa 
			cantidad de daño, dividido como tu 
			quieras, entre cualquier número de 
			ﬁguras opuestas que estén adyacentes 
			a la casilla ocupada por el 
			personaje KO.</item>
        <item>SECRET WARRIORS\n
			Keyword(s): Secret Warriors\n
			Cost: 1\n
			When you build your force, choose the H.A.M.M.E.R., HYDRA,
			or S.H.I.E.L.D. keyword. Characters using this team ability also
			possess the chosen keyword. Uncopyable.
			\n\n
			Antes de revelar tu equipo, elige una 
			de las tres claves: HAMMER, HYDRA 
			o SHIELD. Los personajes que usen 
			este ATA poseen la clave elegida. No 
			puede ser usada por comodines.</item>
        <item>SERPENT SOCIETY\n
            Keyword(s): Serpent Society or Serpent Squad\n
			Cost: 6* (0 if the character possesses the Serpent Society
			team symbol)\n
			Characters using this team ability can use
			Phasing/Teleport.
			\n 
			Los personajes usando este ATA 
			pueden usar Fase / Teleportar.\n\n
			* El ATA cuesta 0 si el personaje 
			posee el símbolo de equipo Serpent 
			Society.</item>
        <item>SHADOWPACT\n
            Keyword(s): Shadowpact\n
            Cost: 1\n
This character ignores the Mystics team ability.
\n\n
			Este personaje ignora la habilidad de 
			equipo Místico.</item>
        <item>SINISTER TWELVE\n
    Keyword(s): Sinister Syndicate\n
    Cost: 4\n
    When you have more characters on the map than each opponent,
    modify the attack value of each character using this team ability by
    +1.</item>
        <item>THE SOCIETY\n
            Keyword(s): Secret Society of Super Villains or
			Society\n
			Cost: 3\n
			Whenever a character using this team ability is
			targeted by Outwit, you roll
			a d6. On a result of 4-6, the opposing
			character that targeted your
			character cannot use Outwit to target
			that character this turn. This
			team ability cannot be used by wild
			cards.
			\n\n
			Cuando un personaje usando este 
			ATA es objevo de un Outwit, puedes 
			tirar 1d6. En un resultado de 4-6, el 
			personaje opuesto que hizo Outwit 
			no puede usarlo sobre este personaje 
			durante este turno. Este ATA no 
			puede ser copiada.</item>
        <item>SPIDER-MAN FAMILY\n
    Keyword(s): Spider-Man Family\n
    Cost: 10* (3 if the character the Spider-Man symbol)\n
    Characters using this team ability possess the Spider-Man team
    ability if they don\'t already, and may use the Spider-Man team
    ability to copy the team abilities of opposing characters as if they
    were friendly. Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>SQUADRON SUPREME\n
            Keyword(s): Squadron Sinister or Squadron
			Supreme\n
			Cost: 5\n
			While at least two friendly characters using this
			team ability are
			adjacent, one of them of your choice can use Mind
			Control. This team
			ability cannot be used by wild cards.
			\n\n
			Cuando el menos dos ﬁguras aliadas 
			usando este ATA están adyacentes, 
			una de ellas puede usar Control 
			Mental. Esta ATA no puede ser usada 
			por Comodines.</item>
        <item>STRATEGIC HOMELAND INTERVENTION, ENFORCEMENT AND LOGISTICS DIVISION\n
			Keyword(s): S.H.I.E.L.D.\n
			Cost: 3\n
			When a friendly character using this team ability uses Outwit,
    Perplex, or Probability Control, modify its range value and the
    minimum range value for the power by +1 for each other friendly
    character using this team ability.
			\n\n</item>
        <item>THUNDERBOLTS\n
            Keyword(s): Thunderbolts\n
            Cost: 8\n
            Once at the
			beginning of the game, choose any one Marvel team ability
			other than
			an Additional team ability, a wild card team ability, or a
			team ability
			that can\'t be used by wild cards. Characters using this
			team ability
			can use the chosen team ability if they can\'t already.
			\n\n
            Al comienzo del juego, elige 
			cualquier habilidad de equipo Marvel 
			(Que no sea ATA, Comodin o 
			cualquier habilidad de equipo que no 
			pueda ser utilizada por comodines). 
			Los personajes usando este ATA 
			pueden usar la habilidad de equipo 
			elegida si no la tenían ya.</item>
        <item>U-FOES\nKeyword(s): U-Foes\nCost: 3\nWhen a character using this
			team ability hits an opposing character with
			a printed damage value of 4 or
			more, increase the damage dealt to that
			character by 1.
			\n\n
            Cuando un personaje usando este 
			ATA golpea a una ﬁgura oponente 
			con un valor de daño impreso de 4 o 
			más, incrementa el daño hecho a ese 
			personaje en 1.</item>
        <item>UNIVERSAL CHURCH OF TRUTH\nKeyword(s): Universal Chruch of Truth\nCost: 4\n
			When an opposing character targets a character using this team ability with an attack and misses, modify the defense value of all character using this team ability by +1 until the end of the turn.
			\n\n
			Cuando una ﬁgura opuesta ataque y 
			falle a un personaje que este usando 
			este ATA, modiﬁca el valor de 
			defensa de todos los personajes 
			usando esta habilidad de equipo en 
			+1 hasta el ﬁnal del turno.</item>
        <item>VILLAINS FOR HIRE\n
    Keyword(s): Villains for Hire\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Choose a copyable team ability an opposing character possesses; 
    characters using this team ability can use that team ability for the 
    entire game.</item>
        <item>WHITE LANTERN CORPS\nKeyword(s): White Lantern Corps\nCost:
			3\nPlace a number of tokens on this card equal to the number of
			characters
			with the White Lantern Corps keyword with which you begin
			the game.
			Immediately before any attack roll, you may remove one token
			to
			modify a friendly character\'s defense value by +1.
			\n\n
            Coloca un número de contadores en 
			esta carta igual al número de ﬁguras 
			con la clave White Lantern Corps con 
			las que empiezas el juego. Inmediatamente 
			antes de cualquier tirada de 
			ataque, puedes retirar un contador 
			para modiﬁcar la defensa de un 
			personaje aliado en +1.</item>
        <item>WILDC.A.T.S\n
    Keyword(s): Wild.C.A.T.s\n
    Cost: 1\n
    Once per turn, when a character using this team ability makes
    an attack roll and one of the dice is a 1, you may reroll 
    that die. Uncopyable.</item>
        <item>WINTER GUARD\n
Keyword(s): Soviet Super-Soldiers, Winter Guard\n
Cost: 1\n
Each character using this team ability may be given a power
action once per game to be dealt 1 unavoidable damage. If you do,
after actions resolve roll a d6 and heal the character of half the
result.
\n\n
			Cada personaje usando esta ATA 
			puede realizar una acción de poder 
			una vez por juego para recibir 1 daño 
			inevitable. Si lo haces, tras resolver la 
			acción tira 1d6 y cura al personaje la 
			mitad del resultado.</item>
        <item>THE WORTHY\n
    Keyword(s): the Worthy\n
    Cost: 1\n
    When a character using this team ability hits an opposing
    character and the attack roll is doubles, place 1 Worthy token on
    this card for each 100 points of the game’s build total. Before any
    attack roll, you may remove one Worthy token from this card and
    modify a target opposing character’s defense values by -1 for this
    attack.\n\n
    A character using this team ability modifies their attack value by
    +1 when attacking a character using The Mighty additional team
    ability or possessing The Mighty keyword.</item>
        <item>X-FORCE\nKeyword(s): X-Force\nCost: 3\nCharacters using this
			team ability ignore the effects of hindering terrain on
			their
			movement.
			\n\n
            Los personajes que usen esta habilidad 
			de equipo  ignoran los efectos 
			del terreno obstaculizado durante su 
			movimiento.</item>
        <item>YOUNG JUSTICE\n
    Keyword(s): Young Justice\n
    Cost: 4\n
    When a character using this team ability would be KO’d, you may
    instead turn this character to its last click but only if you deal 1
    unavoidable damage to an adjacent friendly character using this
    team ability.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>