<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string-array name="bfc">
		<item>ALPHA STRIKE\n
			Before the beginning of each player\'s first turn,
			that player chooses a
			team symbol possessed by an opposing character.
			The first opposing
			character with that team symbol that is defeated is
			worth additional
			victory points equal to half of that character\'s
			point value.</item>
		<item>ANTIMATTER UNIVERSE\n
			Critical hits do not increase damage dealt.
		</item>
		<item>ARMOR WARS\n
			When damage dealt is reduced by any power or effect,
			increase the damage
			dealt by 1 after it is reduced by all other game
			effects.</item>
		<item>ASSEMBLED\n
			When a force has more than four characters on it with
			the same team
			symbol but different names, each character gets +1 to
			its attack
			value when adjacent to a friendly character with the same
			team
			symbol.</item>
		<item>ASTRAL PLANE\n
			Hindering terrain features become clear terrain
			for movement purposes.</item>
		<item>ATLANTIS RISING\n
			All clear grounded terrain is water terrain.
		</item>
		<item>BACK ALLEY BRAWL\n
			Characters who make close combat attacks using
			no powers, feats, or team
			abilities and who are not affected by the
			powers, feats, or team
			abilities of any friendly character get +2 to
			their attack values.
		</item>
		<item>
			BIZARRO WORLD\n
			A critical miss does not deal the attacker
			damage. Instead,
			after the attack resolves the target of the attack is healed of 1
			damage. After a critical hit is resolved, remove an action token
			from the target of the attack if it has one or more action tokens.
			</item>
		<item>BLACKEST NIGHT\n
			Characters can\'t be healed by standard powers or team abilities unless they
			possess the Black Lantern Corps keyword.</item>
		<item>
			BLOOD CURSE\n
			For each character that
			KO\'s one or more opposing characters during a
			turn, roll a d6 at the end of the turn. On a result of 1-3, that
			character is dealt 1 damage.</item>
		<item>BRIGHT LIGHTS\n
			When determining line of fire, ignore Stealth and team abilities that
			duplicate the effects of Stealth.</item>
		<item>BRIGHTEST DAY\n
			Characters do not take pushing damage for receiving a second token to use
			Regeneration or Support.</item>
		<item>COMMUNICATION BREAKDOWN\n
			Before the beginning of the game\'s first turn, the player playing
			Communication Breakdown chooses one combat value; that combat value
			cannot be modified during the game. When rolling a six-sided die
			for Leadership, subtract 1 from the result.</item>
		<item>
			COSMIC RADIATION INTERFERENCE\n
			Hindering terrain markers and blocking terrain markers can\'t be placed.
			(Debris terrain markers and special markers are unaffected.)</item>
		<item>CRITICAL STRIKE\n
			At the beginning of each of the first player\'s turns, place a strike
			token on this card if there are fewer than six strike tokens on
			this card. When a friendly character is attacking a single
			opposing character and the result is a critical hit, you may
			choose to deal damage normally, or deal damage equal to the number
			of strike tokens on this card and then remove all strike tokens
			from this card.</item>
		<item>CROSSWINDS\n
			Character that can use the Flight ability cannot use the Flight or Carry
			ability.</item>
		<item>DAMAGE CONTROL\n
			Remove all objects from the game, none can be brought into the game. All
			debris tokens are ignored for all purposes except for movement. At
			the beginning of each player\'s turn, all destroyed walls and
			blocking terrain (except Barrier markers and terrain in occupied
			squares) are no longer destroyed.</item>
		<item>DARKNESS\n
			Characters with a range value greater than 6 have a range value of 6
			instead. Perplex may not be used to increase a range value to a
			number greater than 6. Powers and abilities that affect characters
			up to 10 squares away instead affect characters only up to 6
			squares away.</item>
		<item>DAY OF DISCORD\n
			Combat values cannot be replaced by the combat values of other
			characters.</item>
		<item>DEBRIS\n
			Each player must place three additional standard objects in addition
			to those included in their force.</item>
		<item>DEEP SHADOWS\n
			Treat all non-blocking terrain as hindering terrain for line of fire
			purposes. Characters that have range values greater than 6 have
			range values of 6 instead, and range values can\'t be modified to a
			value more than 6. Powers, abilities, and effects able to affect
			characters more than 6 squares away instead can only affect
			characters up to 6 squares away.</item>
		<item>DE-FEATED\n
			At the beginning of each player\'s turn, that player must roll a d6.
			On a result of 1, feats assigned to characters controlled by that
			player are ignored until the beginning of the next player\'s turn.
		</item>
		<item>DEFIANCE\n
			When one of your characters makes a critical hit, remove an action
			token from a friendly character that has not been given an action
			(including a free action) this turn.</item>
		<item>DISBANDED!\n
			Ignore all team abilities.</item>
		<item>DISRUPTION\n
			Characters on a themed team cannot use the Probability Control granted by a
			themed team if they already have an action token placed on them.
			When a character on a themed team uses the Probability Control
			granted by a themed team, place two action tokens on the
			character; the character does not take pushing damage from the
			placement of these tokens.</item>
		<item>EARTHQUAKE\n
			At the beginning of each player\'s turn, that player rolls two
			six-sided dice. If the combined result is 2-3, remove this
			Earthquake from the game. Characters without the wing speed symbol
			are each dealt 3 damage.</item>
		<item>EXHAUSTION\n
			Modify all pushing damage by +1.</item>
		<item>
			EXTRAORDINARY DAY\n
			A roll of 11 or 12 on any attack roll is a critical hit.
			A roll of 2 or 3 on any attack roll is a critical miss.
							</item>
		<item>FEARLESS ASSAULT\n
			Characters get +2 to their speed values when they begin move actions in
			their starting areas.</item>
		<item>FIMBULWINTER\n
			Characters with two action tokens modify their defense value by -1.</item>
		<item>THE GREAT ARENA\n
			Any successful attack roll resulting in doubles is a critical hit.
		</item>
		<item>GROUND ZERO\n
			Whenever a character makes a successful close combat attack, roll a
			six-sided die before damage is dealt. On a result of 5 or 6, the
			attack deals 1 additional damage. On a result of 1 or 2, after
			the attack resolves the attacking character is dealt 1
			unavoidable damage.</item>
		<item>GROUNDED\n
			The Carry ability can\'t be used.</item>
		<item>HIGH GRAVITY\n
			Light objects are considered to be heavy objects, and heavy objects
			are considered to be immobile objects. If a character carries
			another character during an action, deal the carrying character
			1 damage after the action resolves.</item>
		<item>INERTIAL INTERFERENCE FIELD\n
			When a character makes an attack using Running Shot, Charge, or
			Hypersonic Speed, reduce damage dealt by 2. Knockback damage is
			reduced by 1.</item>
		<item>INFERNO\n
			At the beginning of your turn, deal 1 damage to each friendly
			character occupying hindering terrain not generated by powers or
			abilities.</item>
		<item>INFILTRATION\n
			When placing characters at the beginning of the game, characters
			that can use Phasing/Teleport, Smoke Cloud, or Stealth on their
			starting positions can be placed into hindering terrain up to
			half their unmodified speed values away from their starting
			areas. Characters that can use the Swim ability on their
			starting positions can be placed in water terrain up to half
			their unmodified speed values away from their starting areas.
							</item>
		<item>INTERNAL STRIFE\n
			Characters get +1 to their attack values whenever they make a close or
			ranged combat attacks against opposing characters with which
			they share the same team symbol.</item>
		<item>ISOLATION\n
			Combat values can\'t be replaced by higher values.</item>
		<item>KNOCKOUT GAS\n
			Characters occupying indoor terrain modify their speed values by -2.
			Characters using Smoke Cloud can place up to eight hindering
			terrain markers.</item>
		<item>KRAKOA THE LIVING ISLAND\n
			Once at the end of each player\'s turn, he or she can choose a target
			opposing character adjacent to an unoccupied square of outdoor
			hindering, blocking, or elevated terrain and make an attack roll
			with an attack value of 9 and a damage value of 2 against the
			target; the target can\'t be knocked back by the attack. If the
			attack succeeds but the character target takes no damage from
			the attack and has zero or one action token, give the target an
			action token.</item>
		<item>LEGENDARY DAY\n
			Abilities can\'t be countered. All characters can use Willpower if they
			can\'t already.</item>
		<item>LOW GRAVITY\n
			Any standard character occupying clear terrain that is hit by an
			attack is knocked back equal to the damage taken.</item>
		<item>LOYALTY\n
			After forces are placed in their starting area but before the first
			player\'s first turn, each wild card must choose a team ability
			that can be copied by wild cards and is possessed by a friendly
			character. The wild card possesses the chosen team ability until
			the end of the game, and can\'t use any other team ability.
							</item>
		<item>MADNESS\n
			Critical hits are critical misses instead, and vice versa. When a
			character uses Support, the target is healed of 1 fewer damage
			on a critical hit.</item>
		<item>MALICE\n
			At the end of each player\'s turn, if none of his or her characters
			made an attack against an opposing character, that player
			chooses a friendly character and deals it 1 unavoidable damage.
							</item>
		<item>MALFUNCTION\n
			Before the beginning of the first turn, starting with the player who
			played this battlefield condition, each player can remove one
			object from the game.</item>
		<item>MISTRUST\n
			When characters that have the same team symbol or team ability are
			adjacent to each other, modify their defense value by -1, to a
			maximum of -1.</item>
		<item>NOWHERE TO HIDE\n
			Squares with objects in them are not hindering terrain.</item>
		<item>ORDINARY DAY\n
			Cancel a single target battlefield condition.</item>
		<item>
			OVERCONFIDENCE\n
			A character with Perplex may use it only on its own
			combat values.</item>
		<item>PACIFICATION\n
			When 4 or more damage would be dealt, reduce damage dealt by 1.
								</item>
		<item>POOR TEAMWORK\n
			Characters can\'t be carried. Characters that have Telekinesis can\'t
			target friendly characters with Telekinesis.</item>
		<item>POWER DAMPENING FIELD\n
			Damage values higher than 3 become 3 instead.</item>
		<item>PROTECT THE INNOCENT\n
			Once per turn as a free action, you may choose to remove from the
			game a bystander token adjacent to a friendly character. No
			victory points are scored for the removed bystander token.
								</item>
		<item>PROXIMITY MINES\n
			At the end of a turn, if any character is in the same square as
			a non-held object or in a square adjacent to a non-held
			object, roll one six-sided die. On a result of 5 or 6, deal 1
			damage (that ignores all effects that reduce damage) to all
			characters in the same square as or adjacent to the object, and
			then remove the object from the game.</item>
		<item>RADIATION LEAK\n
			When a character uses Regeneration or when a character is the
			target of Support, instead of following the rules for those
			abilities, roll one six-sided die and subtract 3 from the
			result. Treat a negative result as damage dealt to the
			character that may not be evaded or reduced.</item>
		<item>RALLY\n
			Whenever the character with the highest point value remaining on your
			force is defeated, remove one action token from all
			characters on your force, as applicable, and then remove the
			defeated character from the game.</item>
		<item>RESISTANCE\n
			Characters can\'t be the target of Outwit when they are adjacent to at
			least one friendly character with the same team symbol.</item>
		<item>RUSHED ASSAULT\n
			The first character to make an attack targeting an opposing
			character during a game gets -2 to its attack value until the
			attack resolves.</item>
		<item>SABOTAGE\n
			Before the beginning of the first round, the player who played this
			battlefield condition may place an action token on any one
			opposing character. Then, continuing clockwise around the
			table, each other player may choose to roll a d6; on a result
			of 4-6, that player may place an action token on any one
			opposing character that does not already have one.</item>
		<item>SHRUNK\n
			All characters with the #giant# damage symbol have the #attack# damage symbol
			instead. All range values are halved, as is the range of all
			effects that have a range.</item>
		<item>
			SKRULL KILL KREW\n
			When a character with Plasticity rolls to break away, subtract two
			from the result (minimum result 1.) When a character using
			Super Senses or Shape Change rolls a d6, subtract one from the
			result (minimum result 1.)</item>
		<item>SKYSCRAPERS\n
			Elevated terrain is blocking terrain.</item>
		<item>TELEKINETIC STRAIN\n
			When Telekinesis is used to place a character or object 6 or more
			squares away from its starting square, the character using the Telekinesis is dealt 1
			unavoidable damage after the action resolves.</item>
		<item>WAR ZONE\n
			A character using Support does not roll one six-sided die when
			targeting another character; instead, it heals the target of
			damage equal to its unmodified damage value.</item>
		<item>WASTELAND\n
			All elevated terrain is grounded hindering terrain. All walls are
			destroyed. All squares adjacent to walls are hindering
			terrain.</item>
		<item>WHITE NOISE\n
			When a character is the target of Outwit or Perplex, its
			controller rolls one six-sided die. On a result of 4-6, the
			target ignores that use of Outwit or Perplex.</item>
	</string-array>
</resources>
