<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <string-array name="feats">
    <item>ALIAS\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Prerequisite: #attack# and #damage#\n
    Choose a
    character. This character can use Shape Change, if it cannot
    already.
    After this feat is used, remove it from the game.</item>
    <item>AMBIDEXTROUS\n
    Cost: Twice the assigned character\'s printed
    range value (Minimum cost 12).\n
    Prerequisite: Range value of 6 or more and one
    #lightning#.\n
    Choose a character. The character now has
    #lightning##lightning#.</item>
    <item>AMBUSH\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Stealth\n
    Choose a character. The
    character gets +2 to its attack value when it makes
    a close combat
    attack while occupying hindering terrain. After the
    attack resolves,
    the character\'s Stealth is countered until the
    beginning of your next
    turn.</item>
    <item>AND STAY DOWN\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: Exploit Weakness or Super
    Strength\n
    Choose a character. When the character makes a close\n
    combat attack without using an object, an attack roll result of 11 or
    12 is
    a critical hit.</item>
    <item>ARMOR PIERCING\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Choose a character. Damage dealt by
    the character may not be reduced below
    1.</item>
    <item>AUTOMATIC REGENERATION\n
    Cost: 12\n
    Prerequisite: Regeneration\n
    Choose a character. Once, at the beginning of your turn, this
    character
    uses Regeneration as a free action.</item>
    <item>BLOOD OATH\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Battle Fury or
    Blades/Claws/Fangs or Willpower \n
    Choose a character. Before the
    beginning of the first turn, choose an
    opposing character. The
    character modifies its attack value by +1
    when attacking the chosen
    opposing character. When the character
    makes a successful close combat
    attack against the chosen character
    and the attack roll is doubles,
    you can choose to treat the damage
    from the attack as penetrating
    damage. If you do, remove this feat
    from the game after the attack
    resolves.</item>
    <item>
      BOOK OF DESTINY\n
      Cost: 4\n
      Prerequisite: Probability Control or
      Super Senses\n
      Choose a character. At the end of your turn, choose an
      opposing character 6
      or fewer squares away from the character to which
      it can draw a clear
      line of fire. Until the beginning of your next
      turn, the chosen
      character can\'t use Outwit or Probability Control,
      and can\'t evade
      attacks. At the beginning of your next turn, remove
      this feat from
    the game.\n</item>
    <item>
      BRILLIANT TACTICIAN\n
      Cost: 20\n
      Prerequisite: Outwit and
      Perplex\n
      Choose a character. Outwit does not need to show in the
      character\'s stat
      slot in order for the character to use this feat.
      When the character
      uses Perplex, the character can affect every target
      friendly
      character that shares a team symbol or keyword with it. The
    character must have clear line of fire to each target.\n</item>
    <item>CALL TO ARMS\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Mastermind or Support\n
    Choose a character. Give the character a power action. Make an attack
    roll (as though making a close combat attack) against an adjacent
    target friendly character that has one or more action tokens and
    that
    is not adjacent to an opposing character. Ignore all modifiers
    for the
    purpose of the attack. If the attack succeeds, remove all
    action
    tokens from the target and deal the target 1 unavoidable
    damage.
    </item>
    <item>CAMOUFLAGE\n
    Cost: 8\n
    Prerequisite: Shape Change\n
    Choose a
    character. When the character is adjacent to a wall or blocking
    terrain, any line of fire for a ranged combat attack drawn to the
    character is blocked.</item>
    <item>CANNONBALL\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Prerequisite: Impervious or Invulnerability
    or Super Strength\n
    Choose a character. When the character is on
    elevated terrain, it can
    move to the next lowest elevation without
    using a
    ladder or stairs. When the
    character is knocked back off of
    elevated
    terrain, it ignores knock
    back damage.</item>
    <item>COMPEL\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Prerequisite: Mind Control\n
    Choose a
    character. When the character uses Mind Control, it can target a
    single friendly character that has already been given an action
    this
    turn. If the attack succeeds, after the action is resolved
    deal 1
    unavoidable damage to the target.</item>
    <item>CONSTRUCT\n
    Cost: 14\n
    Prerequisite: Barrier\n
    Choose a character.
    Any opposing character adjacent to a barrier marker
    placed by the
    character that attempts to move (or would be moved by
    a power,
    ability, or effect possessed by another character) must
    attempt to
    break away. The effect of this feat ignores powers,
    abilities and
    effects that allow a character to break away
    automatically.</item>
    <item>CONTINGENCY PLAN\n
    Cost: 12\n
    Prerequisite: Leadership or
    Mastermind\n
    Choose a character. If the character\'s controller does
    not use all of his
    or her actions for a turn, put a contingency token
    on this card if
    there are two or fewer tokens on this card. When a
    friendly
    character is given an action, you can remove any number of
    tokens
    from this card: The character modifies the friendly
    character\'s
    speed, attack or range value by +1 for each token
    removed.</item>
    <item>COORDINATION\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: Any team symbol\n
    Choose a
    character. Lines of fire to and from the character are not
    blocked by
    characters with the same team symbol.</item>
    <item>DAMAGE SHIELD\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Close Combat Expert,
    Combat Reflexes, Energy Shield/Deflection,
    Flurry, Hypersonic Speed,
    Impervious, Invulnerability, or Poison \n
    Choose a character. When the
    character is the target of a
    successful close combat attack, the
    attacker is dealt 1 damage
    after the attack resolves.</item>
    <item>DARKNESS WITHIN\n
    Cost: 15\n

    Choose a character. (Optional) Once
    per turn immediately before this
    character makes an attack, deal 1
    pushing damage that ignores
    Willpower and team abilities to a single
    target friendly character
    adjacent to the character; this is not an
    attack: The character
    gets +1 to its damage value for that attack. The
    friendly target
    does not receive an action token for this pushing
    damage.</item>
    <item>DISASSEMBLE\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Prerequisite: Force Blast or Energy
    Explosion or Exploit Weakness \n
    Choose a character. When this
    character is given an action and begins or
    ends the action adjacent to
    or in the same square as a target
    special object or standard heavy
    object, you may remove the
    target object from the game and
    replace it with a standard light object
    from outside the game.
    </item>
    <item>DISINTEGRATE\n
    Cost: 7\n
    Prerequisite: Close Combat Expert or
    Exploit Weakness or Poison \n
    Choose a character. When the character
    is given a close combat action,
    before making the close combat attack,
    remove from the game an
    object adjacent to the character or an object
    held by a
    character adjacent to the character.</item>
    <item>DISSENT\n
    Cost: 18\n
    Prerequisite: Outwit\n
    Choose a character.
    When the character uses Outwit, it may choose to
    counter a team
    ability possessed by a single target opposing
    character.</item>
    <item>
      DIVEBOMB\n
      Cost: 10\n
      Modifier: #attack# -1\n
      Prerequisite:
      #flying#\n
      Choose a character. When soaring, the character may make
      close combat
    attacks against grounded characters.\n</item>
    <item>DOUBLE-TIME\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Transporter or #speed# speed
    mode\n
    Choose a character. When the character is not adjacent to an
    opposing
    character and is given a move action, it may move up to
    double its
    unmodified speed value; it may not make attacks during this
    move
    action. At the end of the move, if the character is not a
    transporter, deal it 1 pushing damage that ignores Willpower and
    team
    abilities.</item>
    <item>DRAG\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: #flying#\n
    Choose a character. Give
    the character a power action when it is
    adjacent to a target opposing
    character. If the character
    successfully breaks away, move the
    character up to half its speed
    value and then place the target in an
    unoccupied square adjacent
    to the character. If the target is not a
    flying character and
    occupied a square of elevated terrain, and then
    was placed in a
    square on a lower elevation, deal it 2 damage after
    being placed.
    </item>
    <item>ELITE SNIPER\n
    Cost: 20\n
    Prerequisite: Ranged Combat Expert or
    Super Senses\n
    Choose a character. Ranged combat attacks made by the
    character ignore
    other characters\' Stealth. The character can use the
    Sharpshooter
    ability.</item>
    <item>ENDURANCE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: #attack# and #damage#\n
    Choose
    a character. When the character would be dealt pushing damage,
    you can
    instead choose to deal no damage to the character and put
    an endurance
    token on this card. If there are endurance tokens on
    this card when
    the character is given a non-free action, after the
    action resolves,
    roll a d6. on a result of 1 or 2, deal the
    character unavoidable
    damage equal to the result plus the number
    of tokens on this card,
    then remove all tokens form this card.
    </item>
    <item>ENERVATION\n
    Cost: 7\n
    Prerequisite: Defend or Support\n
    Choose a
    character. During an opponent\'s turn, if an action token would
    be
    given to a friendly character adjacent to the character, roll
    2d6; on
    a result of 9-12, the token is not given.</item>
    <item>ENTANGLE\n
    Cost: 8\n
    Prerequisite: Plasticity\n
    Choose a character.
    Opposing characters attempting to target the
    character with a close
    combat attack must roll one six-sided die
    before making the attack. On
    a result of 1 or 2, the opposing
    character cannot attack the
    character. It is not given an action
    token, but it cannot be given
    another action or make another
    attack that turn.</item>
    <item>ENTRENCH\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Defend or Enhancement\n
    Choose a
    character. Friendly characters adjacent to the character ignore
    knock
    back and critical hits.</item>
    <item>EXTENDED RANGE\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Range greater than 0 and
    less than 9\n
    Choose a character. Before making a ranged combat
    attack, the
    character\'s range may be increased for the duration of
    the
    attack
    by a number of squares up to its unmodified damage value.
    For
    each
    square the range of an attack is increased, decrease the
    damage
    value by 1 (after all other modifiers and replacements) when
    resolving the attack. An attack using Incapacitate does not place
    any
    action tokens on the target.</item>
    <item>FALL BACK\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Combat Reflexes, Super Senses,
    or Phasing/Teleport \n
    Choose a character. When the character makes a
    close combat attack that
    would knock back a single target opposing
    character, the character
    can choose not to knock back the target.
    Instead after the attack
    is resolved move the character directly away
    from the target (the
    character breaks away automatically) for each 1
    damage taken by
    the target.</item>
    <item>
      FASTBALL SPECIAL\n
      Cost: 12\n
      Modifiers: #attack# +2 (see text); /
      #damage#/#giant# +1 (see text)\n
      Prerequisite: Chosen characters must
      have the same team ability
      printed on their bases; see feat text\n
      Choose two characters; if one of them is
      KOd before this feat is used,
      remove the feat from the game.
      Give both characters a power action
      when they are adjacent: The
      first character must have Super Strength
      and the second character
      must be a character without Flight, have
      Toughness and may not
      have a
      damage value higher than 3. The first
      character makes a
      ranged combat
      attack against a single opposing target
      within 6
      squares. Place the
      second character in any square adjacent to
      the
      target to which the
      first character has clear line of fire. If
      the
      attack succeeds, the
      second character deals the damage.
    </item>
    <item>FLASHBANG\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Prerequisite: Smoke Cloud\n
    Choose a
    character. The character can use Smoke Cloud as a free action
    if it
    is
    given a move action immediately before or after using
    Smoke Cloud.
    After this feat it used, remove it from the game.
    </item>
    <item>FORCE FIELD\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Barrier, Defend, Energy
    Shield/Deflection, or Telekinesis \n
    When this character cannot use a
    power or ability that reduces
    damage, this character may use
    Toughness.</item>
    <item>FORTITUDE\n
    Cost: 25\n
    Prerequisite: #attack#\n
    Choose a
    character.
    The character ignores other characters\' Exploit
    Weakness.
    Outwit
    can\'t be used by other characters to counter the
    character\'s
    powers.
    </item>
    <item>FROG LEGS\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Prerequisite: and a point value of 150 or
    less.
    Choose a character. This character can use the Swim ability.
    </item>
    <item>GETAWAY\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Prerequisite: Mastermind\n
    Choose a character.
    Following the resolution of an attack in which the
    character uses
    Mastermind, the character can immediately break
    away automatically and
    move 1 square for each damage that was
    dealt to a friendly character
    via that use of Mastermind.</item>
    <item>GIANT STRIDE\n
    Cost: 9\n
    Prerequisite: #giant#\n
    Choose a
    character. When the character has zero action tokens and is
    moved as
    part of a move or power action, it ignores the effects of
    other
    characters on movement, though it must break away normally.
    </item>
    <item>HAYMAKER\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Modifiers: #attack# -1, #damage#/#giant#
    +2\n

    Choose a character. Give this character a close combat action
    targeting
    a single opposing character. After resolving this action,
    this
    character takes 1 pushing damage that ignores Willpower and team
    abilities.</item>
    <item>HEALING FACTOR\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: Regeneration\n
    Choose a
    character. When this character uses Regeneration, it doesn\'t
    count
    toward your available actions for the turn.</item>
    <item>HEIGHTENED REFLEXES\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Combat Reflexes or
    Energy Shield/Deflection\n
    Choose a character. When the character is
    hit by an attack using Charge,
    Hypersonic Speed, Running Shot, or the
    Move and Attack
    ability, roll one six-sided die before
    damage is dealt. On a
    result of 5 or 6, the character evades the
    attack.</item>
    <item>HOLD THE LINE\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Prerequisite: #attack#, #damage# and
    Leadership or Super Strength\n
    Choose a character. Give the character
    a power action to make a close
    combat attack against an opposing
    character. If the attack
    succeeds, you may modify the character\'s
    attack value by -2 and
    make a close combat attack against a different
    opposing character
    as a free action.</item>
    <item>HOMING DEVICE\n
    Cost: 8\n
    Modifiers: #damage# -1\n

    Choose a
    character. When this character hits an opposing character with
    a close
    combat attack, lines of fire drawn to that opposing
    character until
    the end of your turn are not affected by hindering
    terrain.</item>
    <item>IMMORTAL CONTEMPT\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Deity keyword\n
    Choose a character. The character modifies its attack value by +1
    when
    attacking a character without the Deity or Cosmic keyword that
    has
    a point value less than its own.</item>
    <item>IMPROVISE\n
    Cost: 7\n
    Prerequisite: Close Combat Expert or Perplex
    or Ranged Combat Expert \n
    Choose a character. Once per round, when
    one of the character\'s combat
    values would be modified such that the
    modified value is higher
    than the unmodified value, you can ignore the
    modifier and put an
    Improvise token on this card, if there are fewer
    that three tokens
    on this card. \n
    If there are three tokens on this
    card when the character makes an
    unsuccessful attack roll where the
    result of the roll is doubles,
    you can remove all tokens from this
    card and automatically hit the
    target of the attack (though this is
    not a critical hit.) Remove
    all tokens from this card when the
    character makes a critical hit.
    </item>
    <item>IN CONTACT WITH ORACLE\n
    Cost: 10 per character chosen\n
    Prerequisite: Choose two or more characters; Oracle may not be
    chosen.
    Chosen characters are Agents. As long as it is not the target
    on
    Mind
    Control, when an Agent is given an action you may choose to
    give one of
    its combat values +1 until the beginning of your next
    turn. If Oracle
    is on your force, you may remove her from the
    battlefield at the
    beginning of the game and place her on this
    card. At
    the beginning of
    any of your turns, you may assign a power
    action to
    any Agent with zero
    or one action token and turn Oracle\'s
    dial to any
    click. The Agent
    given the action may use any power
    showing on
    Oracle\'s dial until any
    Agent with zero or one action
    token is given a
    power action to turn
    Oracle\'s dial. If your last
    Agent is
    KOd while
    Oracle is on this card, Oracle is also
    KOd.</item>
    <item>INDOMITABLE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Battle Fury or Willpower\n
    Choose a character. When the character is the target of an
    Incapacitate
    or a Mind Control attack, it gets +2 to its defense
    value.</item>
    <item>INFILTRATE\n
    Cost: 2\n
    Prerequisite: Stealth or Shape Change\n
    Choose a character. This character can ignore other characters for
    movement purposes, but it must end its movement adjacent to an
    opposing character.</item>
    <item>INSIDE INFORMATION\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Prerequisite: The character must
    have at least one keyword.
    Choose a character. When the character
    attacks
    an opposing
    character
    that has any of the keywords possessed by
    the
    character,
    modify the
    character\'s attack value by +2.
    </item>
    <item>INSPIRING COMMAND\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Prerequisite: Leadership or
    Mastermind\n
    Choose a character. Characters with the same team symbol
    as the
    character and a lower point value than the character are not
    dealt
    pushing damage when a second token is placed upon them if they
    are
    adjacent to the character at the beginning of an action.</item>
    <item>INVIGORATE\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Support\n
    Choose a character.
    When the character uses Support, remove one action
    token from adjacent
    friendly characters (maximum three total
    tokens removed.) Characters
    that have action tokens removed from
    them can\'t be given power
    actions
    the same turn this feat is used.
    </item>
    <item>KNOCKDOWN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Incapacitate\n
    Choose a
    character. Once per turn, after the character resolves a
    successful
    close combat action using Incapacitate, if the target
    has only one
    action token, as a free action the character can
    immediately make a
    second close combat attack against the target,
    which gets +2 to its
    defense value for the second attack. If the
    attack succeeds, deal no
    damage, instead, give the target a second
    action token. If the
    character loses Incapacitate before making
    the second attack, it may
    not make the second attack.</item>
    <item>LARGE OBJECT\n
    Cost: 3 per 100 points of the game\'s build
    total\n
    Prerequisite: Super Strength or Telekinesis\n
    When any
    character you
    control uses an object as a weapon, you may
    reduce the
    damage increase
    provided by the object, to a minimum of
    1 damage. The
    character gets
    +1 to its attack value for that
    attack for each 1 damage
    reduced.
    </item>
    <item>
      LAZARUS PIT\n
      Cost: 20 (10 if Ra\'s Al Ghul)\n

      Choose a
      character.
      When the character is
      KOd, remove it from the battlefield,
      place it on
      this card on its
      first
      KOd click, and then place a Special
      marker on the
      square where
      it was
      KOd. At the beginning of each
      player\'s turn, you
      may either
      heal the character of 1 damage or return
      it to the
      battlefield
      on the square with the Special marker. If you
      return the
      character to the battlefield, remove this Lazarus Pit from
      the
      game;
      roll a one six-sided die at the beginning of each of your
      turns. On a
      result of 5 or 6, remove the Special marker from
      the
      battlefield. As
      long as the Special marker is on the
      battlefield, the
      character gains
      Battle Fury, Toughness, and
      Willpower; it may not use
      any of its other
      powers or its team
      ability. When time expires, or if
      all other members
      of the
      character\'s force are
      KOd while the character
      is on this card,
      the character is
      KOd. The character awards victory
      points each time it
    isKOd.</item>
    <item>LIFE MODEL DECOY\n
    Cost: 12\n
    Choose a character. This character
    may not be healed. Damage dealt
    to this character is reduced by 1 if
    it is not reduced or ignored by
    any other effect.</item>
    <item>LONER\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Point value of 100 points or less.
    Choose a character. If no other friendly character on the
    battlefield
    shares any of this character\'s keywords (or this
    character has no
    keywords), modify this character\'s defense
    value by +1 when this
    character has a clear line of fire to
    an opposing character 6 or fewer
    squares away. Only one
    character on a force can be assigned this feat.
    </item>
    <item>
      LOOK! UP IN THE SKY!\n
      Cost: 9\n
      Prerequisite: #flying#\n
      Choose a
      character. When the character is given a move action,
      modify its speed
      value by +2 until the action is resolved.
      A character assigned this
      feat cannot carry other
      characters and automatically breaks away from
      other soaring
    characters.</item>
    <item>LUCKY BREAK\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: #speed# or #swim#\n
    Choose a
    character. When you make an attack roll for the
    character, if the
    result on either of the two dice is a 1,
    you may reroll one die before
    determining the attack roll
    result. You may reroll only once per
    attack roll. If you
    use this feat, remove this card from the game
    after the
    attack resolves.</item>
    <item>LUNGE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Close Combat Expert or
    Leap/Climb\n
    Choose a character. When the character is given an
    action, but
    immediately before it makes a close combat attack, it can
    break away automatically and move up to 2 squares.</item>
    <item>MANEUVER\n
    Cost: 8\n
    Prerequisite: #speed#, Close Combat Expert or
    Combat Reflexes\n
    Choose a character. When the character makes a close
    combat
    attack against a single target opposing character, after
    the
    attack is resolved, put the target in any unoccupied
    square adjacent
    to the character.</item>
    <item>MENTAL SHIELDS\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Prerequisite: Mind Control or
    Willpower\n
    Choose a character. The character is not affected by other
    character\'s Mind Control. When the character uses Mind
    Control, it
    can target only a single opposing character;
    the character takes no
    damage due to the point value of the
    target.</item>
    <item>MERCENARY\n
    Cost: 25 minus 5 for each friendly character with the
    chosen
    team ability, min 10\n
    Prerequisite: No team symbol\n
    Choose a
    character. Before the beginning of the game\'s first
    turn, choose a
    team ability possessed by a friendly
    character. The team ability
    cannot be a wild card, must be
    usable by wild cards and cannot be an
    Additional Team
    Ability. The character is a wild card that can only use
    the
    chosen team ability when adjacent to a friendly character
    possessing that team ability and a higher point value.
    </item>
    <item>MONSTER HUNTER\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Prerequisite: #damage#\n
    Choose a
    character. Modify the character\'s attack value and
    damage value by +1
    when it is given a close combat or
    ranged combat action targeting a
    character with the #giant#
    or #colossus# damage symbol or the Monster
    keyword.</item>
    <item>MOVETHROUGH\n
    Cost: 8\n
    Prerequisite: Charge\n
    Choose a character.
    The character ignores other characters for
    movement purposes, but it
    must still break away, as normal.
    </item>
    <item>NANOARMOR\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: #damage#\n
    Choose a character.
    The character ignores damage dealt by objects
    as well as all modifiers
    to damage dealt to or taken by
    this character due to objects.</item>
    <item>NANOBOTS\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Damage value of 2 or less\n
    Choose a character. When this character is the only character
    adjacent to an object not being held by a character,
    give the
    character a free action and remove the object from
    the game. Heal the
    character of 2 damage.</item>
    <item>NOT SO SPECIAL\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Prerequisite: None\n
    Choose a character.
    Whenever this character attacks an opposing
    character possessing a
    Special Power, if this character
    currently possesses no Special Power
    or Traits, modify this
    character\'s attack value by +1.</item>
    <item>NOVA BLAST\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Pulse Wave\n
    Choose a
    character. When the character uses Pulse Wave, its
    damage does not
    become 1 for the attack. Use the
    character\'s unmodified damage value
    for the attack,
    regardless of how many clear lines of fire can be
    drawn.
    After resolving this action, the character takes 2 pushing
    damage that ignores Willpower and team abilities; remove
    this Nova
    Blast from the game.</item>
    <item>OPPORTUNIST\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Charge or Running Shot or
    Willpower; point value of 50
    points or more. \n
    Choose a character. If
    the character has zero action tokens at
    the end of your turn (before
    tokens are removed from
    characters), put an opportunist token on this
    card if there
    are four or fewer opportunist tokens on this card. When
    the
    character or an adjacent friendly character makes an
    attack, after
    making the roll you can remove any number of
    opportunist tokens from
    this card and modify the result of
    the attack roll by +1 for each
    token removed. If
    opportunist tokens are removed when another
    character makes
    an attack, deal the character 1 unavoidable damage
    after
    the action resolves.</item>
    <item>OUTSMART\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Mastermind or Outwit\n
    Choose a
    character. When a power possessed by the character or an
    adjacent
    friendly character would be countered by an
    opposing character\'s
    power or ability, you and the opposing
    character\'s controller each
    roll 2d6. If your result is
    more, the power is not countered instead.
    </item>
    <item>PASSENGER\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Leap/Climb or
    Phasing/Teleport\n
    Choose a character. When this character uses
    Leap/Climb or
    Phasing/Teleport, it may use the Carry ability. After
    this
    character resolves an action using Passenger, it takes 1
    pushing
    damage that ignores Willpower and team abilities.
    </item>
    <item>POINT BLANK\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Prerequisite: Ranged Combat Expert\n
    Choose a character. Give the character a ranged combat action and
    modify its attack value by +1 if the target of the attack
    is 4 or
    fewer squares away.</item>
    <item>POUNCE\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Modifiers: #attack# +1 / #damage# +1\n
    Prerequisite: Leap/Climb and damage value 1 or 2 \n
    Choose a
    character. Give this character a power action. Move the
    character up
    to its speed value and makes a close combat
    attack as a free action.
    After resolving the attack, the
    character takes 1 unavoidable damage.
    </item>
    <item>POWER BARRAGE\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: #duoatck#\n
    Choose a character. This character may make a close or ranged 
    combat attack as a free action with its attack and damage values 
    modified by -1 for the attack if it deals damage to an opposing 
    character via any of the following powers:\n
    Blades/Claws/Fangs, Energy
    Explosion, Pulse Wave, Quake,
    Incapacitate, Penetrating/Psychic Blast
    or Telekinesis</item>
    <item>
      PRECISION DEMOLITION\n
      Cost: 5\n
      Prerequisite: Close Combat Expert
      or Super Strength\n
      Choose a character. When the character destroys a
      wall or
      blocking terrain, do not place debris markers; instead
      place
      SPECIAL markers to indicate that the wall or blocking
      terrain has been
    destroyed.</item>
    <item>PROTECTED\n
    Cost: 8\n
    
    Choose a character. (Optional) If the
    character does not already
    have two action tokens on it, you may choose to ignore damage dealt
    to the
    character as a result of a single attack. If you do, after
    that
    action is resolved, give the character an action
    token and remove this
    feat from the game. If the character
    already had one action token on
    it, giving it a second
    action token deals pushing damage normally.
    </item>
    <item>PUMMEL\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Combat Reflexes or Close Combat
    Expert or Super Senses \n
    Choose a character. Once per turn, when the
    character has
    zero action tokens and is given a close combat action,
    you
    can ignore the result of one attack roll made for the
    character and
    reroll the dice to obtain a new result.
    </item>
    <item>PYM PARTICLES\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: #damage#,#tavengers#\n
    Choose a character. Once per game, choose one – the character
    has the
    damage symbol; or the character modifies its
    defense value by +1
    against ranged combat attacks. The
    chosen effect lasts until the end
    of the game.</item>
    <item>RECHARGE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Energy Explosion\n
    Choose a
    character. Whenever a total of 2 or more damage is
    taken by opposing
    characters while this character is using
    Energy Explosion, heal this
    character of 1 damage after
    actions resolve.</item>
    <item>REPULSOR\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Modifier: #attack# -1\n
    Prerequisite: Force
    Blast \n
    Choose a character. When the character succeeds at a ranged
    combat attack against a single target opposing character,
    after the
    action is resolve the target is knocked back.
    </item>
    <item>REPULSOR SHIELD\n
    Cost: 25\n

    Choose a character. The character
    ignores other characters Force
    Blast, Psychic Blast, and Ranged Combat
    Expert.</item>
    <item>RETALIATION\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: #damage#, Leap/Climb or
    Blades/Claws/Fangs or Outwit or
    Super Senses, point value of 60 or
    greater \n
    Choose a character. When the character takes damage but
    isn\'t
    defeated by a close combat attack made by an opposing
    character, after the resolution of the attack you can roll
    2d6. on a
    result of 9-11, deal the attacker 1 damage; on a
    result of 12, deal
    the attacker 2 damage. After this feat
    is used, remove it from the
    game.</item>
    <item>REVENGE\n
    Cost: 2 per character on your force\n
    Prerequisite:
    Battle Fury or Willpower\n
    Choose a character. When the character
    makes a close or ranged
    combat attack, modify its attack value by +1
    for each
    friendly character with a higher point value that has been
    knocked out. After this feat is used, remove it from the
    game.</item>
    <item>RIP IT UP\n
    Cost: 20\n
    Prerequisite: Super Strength\n
    Before a
    target character begins a move as part of a move,
    power, or free
    action, give it a light object token from
    outside of the game.</item>
    <item>RUNNING START\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Plasticity or Stealth\n
    Choose a character. Do not halve the character\'s movement when
    it
    begins a move action in hindering terrain.</item>
    <item>SABOTEUR\n
    Cost: 20\n
    Prerequisite: Any non-wild card team
    ability.</item>
    Choose a character. Opposing figures with wild card team
    abilities may
    only copy the team ability of this character
    when copying team
    abilities. If this feat is assigned to
    two or more members of your
    force, this feat is cancelled.
    <item>
      SCATTER!\n
      Cost: 8\n
      Prerequisite: Defend or Leadership
      or Super
      Senses\n
      Choose a character. When the character is
      the target of an
      attack, immediately after the attack
      resolves you can move up to three
      friendly characters
      adjacent to the character up to half their
      unmodified
      speed values. The moved characters must break away
      normally
      and can\'t end their movement adjacent to any
      opposing character.
    </item>
    <item>SHAKE OFF\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Transporter or giant
    character\n
    Choose a character. When the character successfully breaks
    away,
    it deals 1 damage to all adjacent opposing characters.
    </item>
    <item>SHELLHEAD\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Modifier: #defense# +2\n
    Prerequisite:
    Impervious, Invulnerability, or Toughness \n
    Choose a character. The
    ability modifier for Shellhead applies
    only when the character has two
    action tokens placed upon
    it.</item>
    <item>SHOCKWAVE\n
    Cost: 8\n
    Prerequisite: #attack#, Quake\n
    Choose a
    character. Give the character a power action. Make a
    single attack
    roll and compare the result to the defense
    values of all adjacent
    opposing characters. Characters
    against which the attack succeeds are
    dealt no damage, but
    are knocked back 4 squares.</item>
    <item>
      SHOW OFF\n
      Cost: 6\n
      Prerequisite: #duoatc#\n
      Choose a character.
      When using the Duo Attack ability, if this
      character
      KO\'s an opposing
      character with the first attack,
      you may choose to not give this
      character a free action
      for the second attack. Instead, do not give
      this
      character an action token for the action, though the
      action still
      counts towards your available actions.
    </item>
    <item>SIDEKICK\n
    Cost: 10\n

    Choose two characters: The first character
    must have a point
    value at least twice that of the second character.
    The
    two characters must be adjacent in order to use this
    feat. Neither
    character may carry the other. (Optional)
    The second character uses
    the first character\'s
    unmodified defense value instead of its own
    when it is
    attacked by an opposing character.</item>
    <item>SIDESTEP\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: #duoatc#\n
    Choose a character.
    When using the Duo Attack special ability,
    before making the second
    attack the character can attempt
    to move up to 4 squares (it must
    still break away, if
    necessary). If it moves, it must be able to
    attempt the
    second attack after the move.</item>
    <item>SIPHON POWER\n
    Cost: 20\n
    Prerequisite: Wild card team ability\n
    Choose a character. This character has the following team
    ability
    instead of any team ability for team symbols
    printed on its base: Once
    at the beginning of each
    player\'s turn, this character may choose and
    use on that
    turn any team ability that any figure on the battlemap
    possess. This team ability follows all other rules for
    the wild card
    team ability.</item>
    <item>SKULLDUGGERY\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Exploit Weakness or
    Poison\n
    Choose a character. Once per turn when the character deals
    damage to a target opposing character you can roll 2d6;
    on a result of
    9-12, you can give an action token to the
    target if it has zero action
    tokens.</item>
    <item>SLIPPERY\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Prerequisite: Combat Reflexes or Defend or
    defense value greater than
    17 \n
    Choose a character. The character
    ignores other characters\'
    Plasticity, and it fails to break away only
    on a result
    of 1.</item>
    <item>SNEAK\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Stealth or Super Senses\n
    Choose a
    character. When the character is given a move action,
    it is not
    required to end its movement when it becomes
    adjacent to an opposing
    character. Otherwise it must
    break away normally.</item>
    <item>SPOTTER\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Ranged Combat Expert\n
    Choose a
    character. When another friendly character makes a
    ranged combat
    attack against a target opposing figure,
    modify the friendly
    character\'s attack value by +1 if
    this character has a clear line of
    fire to the target and
    the target is within this character\'s range.
    </item>
    <item>STARSTRUCK ADMIRER\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Prerequisite: Celebrity keyword.
    Choose a character. The character can use
    Incapacitate
    with a range of
    8, if it can\'t already. After this feat
    is
    used, remove it from the
    game.
    </item>
    <item>
      STREAK OF LUCK\n
      Cost: 5\n
      Prerequisite: #attack#, #damage#\n
      Choose a character. Each time an attack roll fails against the
      character, put a luck token on this card if there are
      fewer than three
      tokens on this card. If there are luck
      tokens on this card when the
      character makes a critical
      miss, the character is not dealt
      unavoidable damage; after
      the attack is resolved, remove all luck
      tokens from this
      card. If there are luck tokens on this card when the
      character makes a critical hit, modify the character\'s
      damage value
      by +X, where
      X equals the number of luck tokens on this card;
      after the
      attack is resolved, remove all luck tokens from
    this card.</item>
    <item>STUNNING BLOW\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Incapacitate\n
    Choose a
    character. When the character makes a
    successful attack using
    Incapacitate, in addition to the normal effect of
    Incapacitate the
    character may deal damage
    equal to its unmodified damage value. The
    attacker may
    choose to divide damage dealt among the successfully hit
    targets,.</item>
    <item>SUBMERGED\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: #swim#\n
    Choose a character.
    When it is not your turn, if the character occupies
    water terrain, lines of fire
    drawn to it are blocked.
    </item>
    <item>SUNDER\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Prerequisite: Blades/Claws/Fangs\n
    Choose a
    character. When the character succeeds at a close
    combat attack
    targeting blocking terrain, a wall, or an
    object, it deals 3 damage.
    </item>
    <item>SUPPRESSIVE FIRE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Enhancement or Ranged
    Combat Expert or Sharpshooter \n
    Choose a character. At the end of
    your turn, you can
    choose a target opposing character 8 or fewer
    squares
    away to which the character can draw a clear line of
    fire; give
    the chosen character a Suppression token.
    Until the beginning of your
    next turn, if the chosen
    character would be given a ranged combat
    action or make a
    ranged combat attack, its controller must roll a d6;
    on a
    result of 1 or 2, the attack can\'t be made or the action
    can\'t
    be given (the action can still be given to another
    character, if
    possible). At the beginning of your next
    turn after the character uses
    this feat, remove all
    Suppression tokens from opposing characters and
    then
    either remove this feat from the game or roll a d6; on a
    result of
    1–4 give an action token to this character (the
    token deals pushing
    damage normally).</item>
    <item>SWINGLINE\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Modifier: #speed# +1 \n
    Prerequisite:
    #speed#\n
    Choose a character. The character ignores hindering terrain
    for
    movement purposes. If the character succeeds at a ranged
    combat
    attack against a target opposing character with
    the #flying# speed
    symbol, the target gains Earthbound
    until the beginning of its
    controller\'s next turn.</item>
    <item>TACTICS\n
    Cost: 20\n
    Prerequisite: Leadership and any team
    symbol\n
    Choose a character. When the character uses Leadership, on a
    result of 3-6 add an extra action to the other action
    granted by
    Leadership to your available actions for the
    turn. This extra action
    can be used only by a friendly
    character with the same team symbol as
    the character.
    </item>
    <item>TAUNT\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Modifier: #attack# +1\n
    Prerequisite: Range
    value greater than 0 \n
    Choose a character. Give this character a
    power action; it
    makes a ranged combat attack targeting a single
    opposing
    character to which it has a clear line of fire within 6
    squares. If the attack succeeds, it deals no damage. The
    target must
    either attempt to move adjacent to or attack
    this character next turn.
    </item>
    <item>TAKEDOWN\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: Incapacitate or Plasticity\n
    Choose a character. If an opposing character makes an
    unsuccessful
    close combat attack against the character,
    after the action is
    resolved give the opposing character
    an extra action token if it has
    zero or one action token.
    If the opposing character already has one
    action token on
    it, giving it a second action token deals pushing
    damage
    normally.</item>
    <item>TELEKINETIC REACH\n
    Cost: 12\n
    Prerequisite: Telekinesis\n
    Choose a
    character.When using Telekinesis, if A is within 6
    squares and is an object, B may be up to 10 squares from A. All other
    rules
    for Telekinesis apply normally.</item>
    <item>TERRIFY\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Modifier: #attack# -1 \n
    Prerequisite: Battle
    Fury or Incapacitate or Mind Control\n
    Choose a character. Give the
    character a power action and make
    a single close combat attack as a
    free action (the attack
    deals no damage). Compare the result to the
    defense
    values of all adjacent opposing target characters,
    maximum four
    targets. Each target against which the
    attack succeeds is knocked back
    a number of squares equal
    to half its speed values (targets are not
    dealt knock
    back damage). If the attack roll is doubles and succeeds
    against the target, also give an action token to the
    target if it has
    zero or one action token (the target is
    not dealt pushing damage for
    this token).</item>
    <item>THUNDERING BLOW\n
    Cost: 20\n
    Prerequisite: #attack# attack value
    11 or higher\n
    Choose a character. After the resolution of a
    successful attack
    by the character that causes an opposing character
    to
    take 3 or more damage, the damage value of all friendly
    characters
    attacking that opposing character during that
    turn is modified by +1
    until an attack against that
    opposing character is unsuccessful. If
    this feat is
    assigned to two or more characters on your force, this
    feat is canceled.</item>
    <item>THWART\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Prerequisite: Mastermind or Outwit\n
    Choose a
    character. Give the character a power action. Place a
    thwart token on
    a target feat card assigned to a
    character that is 10 or fewer squares
    from the character
    and to which the character has a clear line of
    fire. The
    target feat is ignored until a character to which it is
    assigned is given a power action specifically to remove
    the thwart
    token.</item>
    <item>TOXIC BURST\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Poison\n
    Choose a character.
    For purposes of resolving its Poison power,
    the character is adjacent
    to opposing characters up to
    two squares away to which it has a clear
    line of fire.
    After dealing damage with Poison, using Toxic Burst, the
    character is dealt 1 unavoidable damage.</item>
    <item>TRIAGE\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Prerequisite: Support\n
    Choose a character.
    When the character uses Support and succeeds, the
    resulting healing can be divided
    among the target and any other
    friendly characters (none
    of which may be adjacent to an opposing
    character) to
    which the character is adjacent and that the attack roll
    would hit (ignore all combat value modifiers). The target
    must be
    healed of at least 1 damage.</item>
    <item>TRICK SHOT\n
    Cost: 20\n
    Prerequisite: Plasticity or Ranged Combat
    Expert\n
    Choose a character. When making an attack from a square that
    is
    not adjacent to an opposing character, the character
    ignores Stealth
    and team abilities that duplicate the
    effects of Stealth, and it
    ignores characters and
    hindering terrain for line of fire purposes.
    </item>
    <item>UNSTOPPABLE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Prerequisite: Super Strength\n
    Choose a
    character. The character ignores the effects of
    hindering terrain for
    movement purposes. Once when given
    a move action, the character can
    make a close combat
    attack targeting blocking terrain or a wall as a
    free
    action. If the attack succeeds, the character can
    continue the
    rest of its movement, if any, after making
    the attack.</item>
    <item>VAMPIRISM\n
    Cost: 12\n
    Prerequisite: Blades/Claws/Fangs\n
    Choose a
    character. The character can use Steal Energy if it
    can\'t already.
    </item>
    <item>VAULT\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Prerequisite: Combat Reflexes or Leap/Climb\n
    Choose a character. After the character resolves a close combat
    action, it may be placed in any square in which it may
    legally be
    placed adjacent to a target of the action at
    the same elevation as the
    target.</item>
    <item>VENDETTA\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: #attackk# and #defense# and
    #damage#\n
    Choose a character. At the beginning of your first turn,
    choose
    an opposing character with a point value greater than
    this
    character. Modify the attack value of this character
    by +1 when it is
    making a close or ranged combat attack
    against the chosen character.
    If this character defeats
    the chosen character, you score additional
    victory points
    equal to half the chosen character\'s point value. If
    the
    chosen character defeats this character, the chosen
    character\'s
    controller scores additional victory points
    equal to half this
    character\'s point value.</item>
    <item>
      WARBOUND\n
      Cost: 5 per character on your force with the chosen
      keyword\n
      Prerequisite:
      <item>A single, common keyword.</item>
      Choose a character. Choose a keyword. All characters on
      your force
      that have the keyword are assigned this feat.
      When a target friendly
      character assigned this feat is
      given an action, instead of giving it
      an action token,
      you can give the action token for the action to an
      adjacent friendly character that has the chosen keyword,
      has zero
      action tokens, and has a point value equal to at
      least half of the
      target\'s point value.
    </item>
    <item>WHIRLWIND\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Prerequisite: Force Blast\n
    Choose a
    character. When the character uses Force Blast, the
    result of the
    six-sided die roll can be split among
    multiple target adjacent
    opposing characters. The targets
    are otherwise affected normally by
    Force Blast.</item>
  </string-array>
</resources>
