<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="glossary">
        <item>3-D OBJECT\n
			A three-dimensional sculpture marked with the #3d#
			symbol.</item>
        <item>ABILITY\n
			A capability possessed by a character, indicated by a
			symbol on its
			base and/or explained on its character card.</item>
        <item>ACTION\n
			A character’s attack, move, or use of a power or
			ability.</item>
        <item>ACTION TOKEN\n
			A coin, bead, or some other item used to indicate
			that a character has
			been given an action (other than a free action)
			and how many actions
			(other than free actions) that character has been
			given since it last
			cleared.</item>
        <item>ACTION TOTAL\n
			The number of actions a player has available to
			give to his or her
			characters on each of that player’s turns.</item>
        <item>ACTIVATE\n
			To initiate the use of a power or ability. A power or
			ability can be
			activated by an action given to a character.</item>
        <item>ACTIVE PLAYER\n
			The player whose turn it is.</item>
        <item>ADJACENT SQUARES\n
			All squares on the battlefield that touch a
			given square, including
			those on the diagonal. Terrain effects can
			cause 2 squares that share
			a border to not be adjacent.</item>
        <item>ATTACK\n
			Part of an action that includes an attack roll to
			determine whether one
			character hits another.</item>
        <item>ATTACK ROLL\n
			The result of rolling 2d6 when a character makes a
			close combat or
			ranged combat attack.</item>
        <item>ATTACK TOTAL\n
			The combined result when an attack roll is added
			to an Attack Value,
			including all game effects.</item>
        <item>ATTACK VALUE\n
			A number that represents a character’s ability to
			successfully hit a
			target in combat.</item>
        <item>ATTACKER\n
			The character initiating an attack.</item>
        <item>BASE\n
			The piece of plastic on which a figure is mounted.</item>
        <item>BASED\n
			A character that has an opposing character occupying an
			adjacent
			square.</item>
        <item>BATTLEFIELD\n
			The map where a HeroClix game takes place.</item>
        <item>BLOCKING TERRAIN\n
			Terrain that prevents movement and an attacker
			from drawing a clear line of
			fire. Squares within a brown border are
			blocking terrain.</item>
        <item>BOUNDARY LINE\n
			The colored line indicating the type and
			outermost squares of an area of
			terrain.</item>
        <item>BREAK AWAY\n
			To move away from adjacent opposing characters.
		</item>
        <item>BUILD TOTAL\n
			The maximum value allowed when the point values of
			all elements of a
			player’s force for a game are added together.</item>
        <item>BYSTANDER TOKEN\n
			A disc with a graphical representation of a
			character on it, rather
			than a figure, that can be included as part of
			your force.</item>
        <item>CHARACTER\n
			The playing piece that represents a personality in
			the game.</item>
        <item>CHARACTER CARD\n
			A card specific to a particular HeroClix
			character that is printed
			with information relevant to that character,
			such as powers,
			character background, first appearance, and so on.
		</item>
        <item>CLEAR TERRAIN\n
			Areas of the battlefield where a character can
			move or make a ranged
			combat attack without penalty.</item>
        <item>CLEARING\n
			Removing action tokens from a character at the end of
			your turn.</item>
        <item>CLICK\n
			A single turn of the combat dial resulting in a “click”
			that can be
			felt and heard.</item>
        <item>CLICK NUMBER\n
			A number that represents the sequence number of
			each portion of the
			character’s dial.</item>
        <item>CLOSE COMBAT ACTION\n
			An action given to a character that allows
			it to make a close combat
			attack.</item>
        <item>CLOSE COMBAT ATTACK\n
			A melee or hand-to-hand attack.</item>
        <item>COLLECTOR’S NUMBER\n
			An identifying number specific to a
			particular character in a set.
		</item>
        <item>COLOSSAL CHARACTER\n
			A character with the Colossal Stamina
			ability and Great Size ability,
			usually indicated by the #colossal#
			damage symbol on its base.</item>
        <item>COMBAT DIAL\n
			The piece of plastic under a character’s base, upon
			which the
			character’s powers and combat values are printed.</item>
        <item>COMBAT VALUES\n
			The four numbers visible through the stat slot on
			a character’s combat
			dial, and the number next to the lightning
			bolt(s) on a character’s
			base.</item>
        <item>COPY\n
			A multiple of a game element. For example, a force can
			contain more
			than one copy of a non-Unique character.</item>
        <item>COUNTER\n
			A game effect that causes another power, ability, or
			effect to no
			longer be possessed by a character.</item>
        <item>CONTINUAL\n
			The special ability of a special object with the
			Continual keyword is not
			ignored while being held or moved</item>
        <item>CRITICAL HIT\n
			Any roll of the dice that results in two 6s
			showing.</item>
        <item>CRITICAL MISS\n
			Any roll of the dice that results in two 1s
			showing.</item>
        <item>D6 (OR 2D6)\n
			An abbreviation for “six-sided die” (or “two
			six-sided dice”).</item>
        <item>DAMAGE\n
			A change in a character’s condition that brings it
			closer to being
			defeated, causing a player to click the combat dial of
			the character
			in a clockwise direction.</item>
        <item>DAMAGE DEALT\n
			The number of clicks an attacking character deals
			to a target.</item>
        <item>DAMAGE TAKEN\n
			The number of clockwise clicks applied to a target
			after damage is
			dealt.</item>
        <item>DAMAGE VALUE\n
			A number that represents the number of clicks of
			damage a character
			can deal with a successful attack.</item>
        <item>DEFEATED\n
			A character that is knocked out and removed from the
			game.</item>
        <item>DEFENSE VALUE\n
			A number that represents a character’s ability to
			avoid being hit.
		</item>
        <item>DOUBLES\n
			The result of rolling the same number on 2d6 (such as
			two 4s).</item>
        <item>DUO CHARACTER\n
			A character with the Duo Attack ability, usually
			indicated by the
			#duo# attack symbol.</item>
        <item>EDGE\n
			One of the outermost boundaries of a map or an area of
			terrain.</item>
        <item>EFFECT\n
			A power, ability, or other rule than can affect a game.
		</item>
        <item>ELEVATED\n
			On a square of elevated terrain.</item>
        <item>ELEVATED TERRAIN\n
			Terrain on the map that is located above
			another level of the map. Squares
			inside the boundary of a red line
			are elevated terrain.</item>
        <item>ELEVATION LEVEL\n
			The relative height that a square of elevated
			terrain is located in
			comparison to other squares on the map.</item>
        <item>EVADE\n
			To avoid being hit by an attack that would normally be
			successful.
		</item>
        <item>EVENT DIAL\n
			A dial used to create a dynamically changing
			scenario during a game.\n
			Event Dials with a point cost added to your force build are subject only to the rules
of the event and the judge’s discretion.
		</item>
        <item>FEAT\n
			Special training or abilities that can be possessed by a
			qualifying
			character, represented by a card assigned to the character.
		</item>
        <item>FIGURE\n
			The sculptural representation of a character that is
			mounted on its
			base.</item>
        <item>FIRST PLAYER\n
			The person who takes the first turn in a game.
		</item>
        <item>FLIER\n
			A character using the Flight ability, usually indicated
			by the
			#flight# or #transFlight# speed symbols.</item>
        <item>FORCE\n
			The team of characters controlled by a player.</item>
        <item>FORMAT\n
			The set of rules that will be in effect during a
			HeroClix game.</item>
        <item>FREE ACTION\n
			An action that doesn’t give an action token to a
			character and does not
			affect the action total for this turn.</item>
        <item>FRIENDLY CHARACTERS\n
			Characters that you control, and characters
			controlled by an allied teammate.
		</item>
        <item>GAME EFFECT\n
			See “EFFECT”</item>
        <item>GENERIC KEYWORDS\n
			• Animal\n
			• Armor\n
			• Brute\n
			• Celebrity\n
			• Cosmic\n
			• Deity\n
			• Detective\n
			• Future\n
			• Herald\n
			• Kid\n
			• Martial
			• Artist\n
			• Monster\n
			• Mutant\n
			• Mystical\n
			• Past\n
			• Police\n
			• Politician\n
			• Psychic\n
			• Reporter\n
			• Robot\n
			• Ruler\n
			• Scientist\n
			• Soldier\n
			• Spy\n
			• Teen\n
			• Vehicle\n
			• Warrior</item>
        <item>GIANT\n
			A character with the Giant Reach ability and Great Size
			ability,
			usually indicated by damage symbol.</item>
        <item>GOLDEN AGE\n
			Golden Age events have no restrictions on the
			player’s force other than
			standard HeroClix rules. Between the event
			format (see below) and
			special rules (established in
			the event
			description), other rules may be applied to the force
			construction.
		</item>
        <item>GRENADE POOL\n
			Number of grenades a character starts with.</item>
        <item>GRENADE TYPE(S)\n
			The different types of grenades usable. Frag,
			Ink, Smoke, Thermite,
			Plasma and Flashbang.</item>
        <item>GROUNDED\n
			Characters, objects, and terrain that are not
			elevated. Also known as elevation
			level 1.</item>
        <item>HEALING\n
			Restoring health that has been reduced by damage by
			clicking the combat dial
			of a character in a counterclockwise
			direction.</item>
        <item>HEAVY OBJECT\n
			An object that can be carried or moved and
			modifies a character’s
			Damage Value by +2 when used in a close combat
			attack or deals 3
			damage when used in a ranged combat attack. Heavy
			object tokens
			have a red border.</item>
        <item>HINDERING TERRAIN\n
			An area containing trees, furniture, debris,
			objects, and other
			similar items that might obstruct a character’s
			actions. Squares
			inside the border of a green line are hindering
			terrain.</item>
        <item>HIT\n
			When the result of 2d6 and the attacker’s Attack Value is
			equal to or
			greater than the Defense Value of the target and the
			target does
			not evade the attack.</item>
        <item>IGNORES\n
			Is not affected by or treats the stated property or
			effect as if it
			didn’t exist or happen.</item>
        <item>IMMOBILE OBJECT\n
			An object that can’t be carried, placed, or
			moved by any game effect.
			Immobile object tokens have a blue border.
		</item>
        <item>INDOMITABLE\n
			A character using the Indomitable ability usually
			indicated by the
			#indomitable# defense symbol.</item>
        <item>
			INDOORS\n
			Anywhere on a battle map labeled “Indoor” or “Indoors”
			or
			inside a yellow
			boundary line on a map labeled “Indoor/Outdoor.”
		</item>
        <item>INTERSECTION\n
			Squares that meet a given square at that square’s
			corners are considered
			diagonal from the given square.</item>
        <item>KEYWORD\n
			A special trait of a character. Players create themed
			teams based
			on character keywords.</item>
        <item>KNOCK BACK\n
			Movement away from an attacker due to the force of
			its attack.</item>
        <item>KNOCK BACK DAMAGE\n
			Damage dealt to a character when its knock
			back path intersects with a
			wall, the edge of the map, the boundary
			of
			elevated terrain, or
			the boundary of blocking terrain.</item>
        <item>KNOCK BACK PATH\n
			The line of squares a knocked back character
			passes through if
			otherwise uninterrupted.</item>
        <item>KNOCKED OUT\n
			A character with KO symbols showing on its combat
			dial; such a
			character is defeated.</item>
        <item>KO’D\n
			Knocked out or defeated.</item>
        <item>LIGHT OBJECT\n
			An object that can be carried or moved and
			modifies a character’s
			Damage Value by +1 when used in a close combat
			attack, or deals 2
			damage when used in a ranged combat attack. Light
			object tokens
			have a yellow border.</item>
        <item>LINE OF FIRE\n
			The path between a character using a game effect
			(such as a ranged
			combat attack) and the target, square, object,
			terrain, or other
			game effect.</item>
        <item>LOST POWER\n
			When a power is no longer showing on a character’s
			combat dial after
			the character takes damage or is healed.</item>
		<item>LOST ABILITY\nWhen an ability is no longer possessed by a
			character after a character’s combat symbols, team symbols,
			or trait symbols have been modified.</item>
        <item>MAP\n
			A gridded space representing the area in which a HeroClix
			game
			takes place.</item>
        <item>MODERN AGE\n
			Modern Age events restrict the player’s force to
			being made up of only
			characters and possibly objects. All characters
			must be from the
			Modern Age sets. The following HeroClix sets comprise the Modern Age. Any sets
not included on this list are considered to be Golden Age: Brightest Day, DC 75th
Anniversary, Giant-Size X-Men, Green Lantern, Green Lantern Corps Fast Forces, WizKids
2011 Exclusives, Street Fighter, Crimebusters Fast Forces, Captain America, Warriors of
Asgard Fast Forces, Superman, Battle for Smallville Fast Forces, The Incredible Hulk, Smash
Fast Forces, Infinity Gauntlet, Galactic Guardians, Annihilators Fast Forces, The Avengers
Movie, The Avengers Movie Starter, Dark Knight Rises, Giant-Size X-Men Fast Forces, War
of Light Fast Forces, Chaos War, Chaos War Fast Forces, WizKids 2012 Exclusives, Star Trek
Tactics: Away Team, Justice League New 52, Justice League New 52 Fast Forces, DC
HeroClix - 10th Anniversary, Marvel HeroClix - 10th Anniversary, TabApp, Batman, Batman
Fast Forces, No Man’s Land, Sreets of Gotham, Streets of Gotham Fast Forces and any
 Marvel, DC or Street Fighter sets released after any Modern Age set.
			Objects must either be standard
			objects or special objects from the
			Modern Age sets.
			Alternate Team
			Ability cards are permitted in Modern Age events regardless of
			the set
			they were
			originally printed. Between the event format and special
			rules, other rules may
			be applied to the force construction.\n
			At present the ships of Star Trek: Tactics are NOT part of any HeroClix Ages. Characters from these
sets are not ships and are considered Golden Age.
			</item>
        <item>MODIFIER\n
			A number that increases or decreases a combat value,
			damage dealt,
			or damage taken.</item>
        <item>MOVE\n
			What a character does when traveling between 2 squares
			and
			each square
			in between is identified as being traveled through.
			</item>
        <item>MOVE ACTION\n
			An action given to a character that allows it to
			move up to its
			speed value in squares and/or make a break away
			attempt.</item>
        <item>NAMED POWER\n
			A power with a character-specific label in capital
			letters,
			followed by the name of a standard power in parentheses.
		</item>
        <item>NO DAMAGE\n
			An attack that deals no damage can’t have the damage
			modified by
			powers or team abilities.</item>
        <item>OBJECT TOKENS\n
			Round pieces of cardboard that represent objects
			on the map.</item>
        <item>OPPOSING CHARACTERS\n
			Characters controlled by an opponent.
		</item>
        <item>
			OUTDOORS\n
			Anywhere on a battle map labeled “Outdoor” or
			“Outdoors” or not inside a
			yellow boundary line on a map labeled
			“Indoor/Outdoor”.</item>
        <item>PENETRATING DAMAGE\n
			Damage dealt that can’t be reduced.</item>
        <item>PLACE (OR PUT)\n
			To place (or put) a character or other game
			element in a position
			on the map; a character that previously
			occupied
			another position
			on the map is not considered to have moved
			if it was
			placed.
						</item>
        <item>POSSESS\n
			To directly have a power, ability, or effect printed
			on
			a card or
			dial—not simply used via another power, ability, or
			effect.
		</item>
        <item>POWER ACTION\n
			An action given to a character that allows it to
			use a power,
			ability, or feat.</item>
        <item>POWERS\n
			A character’s special abilities. Powers are represented
			on a
			character’s combat dial by colored squares surrounding the
			character’s combat values and by similarly colored circles on a
			character’s character card.</item>
		<item>PRIME\nA character rank represented by a green ring
			around the outer edge of a character’s base. Only one Prime
			character can be added to a given force.</item>
        <item>PUSH\n
			To give a character a second action token before the
			first
			action
			token is removed.</item>
        <item>PUSHED\n
			A character that has been given a second action token.
		</item>
        <item>PUSHING DAMAGE\n
			Damage dealt (typically when a character
			receives a second action
			token) that can’t be evaded, reduced,
			ignored, or transferred
			unless a game effect specifically says so.
		</item>
        <item>RANGE\n
			The distance (in squares) between a character and a
			target square,
			counting from the center of one square to the target
			square.</item>
        <item>RANGE VALUE\n
			The maximum distance (in squares) at which the
			character can use a
			ranged combat attack to attack a target.</item>
        <item>RANGED COMBAT ACTION\n
			An action given to a character that
			allows
			it to make a ranged
			combat attack.</item>
        <item>RANGED COMBAT ATTACK\n
			An attack that requires an unblocked line
			of fire to a target up to
			the character’s range value away in
			squares.
		</item>
		<item>RELIC\nA special object that is Immobile and can’t be
			destroyed. Characters occupying a square containing a relic
			may be given a power action and then roll a d6 that can’t be
			rerolled. On a result matching the relic value noted on the
			object, the relic is placed on the character’s card.</item>
        <item>REMOVED FROM THE BATTLEFIELD\n
			A character, object, or other
			game
			piece that is removed from the
			map, but still eligible to return
			to the
			game if certain
			conditions are met.</item>
        <item>REMOVED FROM THE GAME\n
			A character, object, or other game piece
			permanently removed from
			the current game.</item>
        <item>REPLACEMENT VALUE\n
			A value that is substituted for one of a
			character’s combat
			values.</item>
        <item>RESOLVE\n
			Completing an action and determining its effects,
			including any of the
			following\n
			declaring the action, completing a
			move, rolling a die or dice, taking any
			free actions allowed by the
			declared action, dealing damage,
			taking damage, assigning action
			tokens, and applying pushing
			damage.</item>
		<item>RESOURCES\nA game effect assigned to your force or a
			character on your force. The effects of each resource are
			defined on the resource’s instruction card.</item>
        <item>RIM\n
			The squares with the red boundary line running through
			them
			along
			the edge of an area of elevated terrain.</item>
        <item>ROLL\n
			Using a die or dice to determine a random result. All
			dice
			must be
			rolled together when more than one die is needed.</item>
        <item>ROUND\n
			A measure of time during which all players take a single
			turn.
				</item>
        <item>SCENARIO\n
			Special rules for a particular HeroClix game, as
			agreed upon by all
			players before the game begins.</item>
        <item>SET SYMBOL\n
			An icon on a character’s base that marks it as part
			of a particular
			HeroClix set.</item>
        <item>SHARPSHOOTER\n
			A character using the sharpshooter ability,
			usually indicated by
			the #sharpshooter# attack symbol.</item>
		<item>SHIP\nA ship is another name for a character; some character
			cards and game effects refer to “ships” without mentioning
			characters. The terms may be used synonymously. For
			example, an effect that says to target a ship may target a
			character, and vice versa.</item>
        <item>SPECIAL OBJECT\n
			An object token or 3-D object printed with the
			#3d# symbol.</item>
        <item>SPECIAL POWER\n
			A power whose name and effects are explained on
			a
			character’s
			character card.</item>
        <item>SPEED VALUE\n
			The maximum number of squares a character can move
			in an action.
				</item>
        <item>STANDARD CHARACTER\n
			A character with the standard combat
			symbols
			or abilities.</item>
        <item>STANDARD POWER\n
			A power or ability whose effects are described
			on the Powers and
			Abilities Card.</item>
        <item>STARTING AREA\n
			An area inside the boundary of a purple line.
		</item>
        <item>STARTING POSITION\n
			The position on the combat dial that
			represents a character’s combat
			values at the beginning of a game.
			This position is designated by
			the number 1 on the click, and/or a
			vertical green line to the
			left of one set of combat values.</item>
        <item>STAT SLOT\n
			The “window” in a character’s base through which the
			character’s
			combat dial is visible.</item>
        <item>SUCCESSFUL ATTACK ROLL\n
			An attack roll that grants an attack
			total high enough to equal or
			exceed the target’s defense value,
			regardless as to whether or
			not the target evades the attack.</item>
        <item>SURVIVING CHARACTER\n
			A character that has not been defeated
			when
			a game ends.</item>
        <item>SWIMMER\n
			A character using the Swim ability, usually indicated
			by the
			#swim# or #transSwim# speed symbols.</item>
        <item>TACTICS\n
			Additional rules and effects that can be employed in a
			game of HeroClix if
			allowed by the agreed-upon format of the game.
		</item>
        <item>TARGET\n
			The character or characters against which an attack is
			being made or
			a power is being used.</item>
        <item>TEAM ABILITIES\n
			Special abilities that a character possesses
			due
			to its membership in a
			group, as indicated by a team symbol
			printed on
			the character’s
			base.</item>
        <item>TEAM SYMBOL\n
			A symbol printed on a character’s base that
			identifies it as a
			member of a group and possessing the associated
			team ability. Not
			all characters have team symbols.</item>
        <item>TERRAIN\n
			Map features that represent water, trees, rocks, cars,
			walls,
			buildings, and other physical features that might appear on
			the
			battlefield.</item>
        <item>TERRAIN MARKERS\n
			Square pieces of cardboard used to represent
			different types of
			terrain, such as barriers, clouds of smoke,
			destroyed walls or
			objects, and special items required by scenarios.
		</item>
        <item>THEMED TEAM\n
			A force composed of characters (other than
			bystander tokens) that
			share a single common keyword.</item>
        <item>THIS CHARACTER\n
			The phrase “this character” always refers to
			the
			active character or
			the character using a power.</item>
		<item>TINY\nA character with the Tiny Size ability, usually indicated by
			#tiny# damage symbol.</item>
        <item>TRAIT ABILITY\n
			An aspect or capability of a character that it
			possesses at all
			times, regardless of how its combat dial is turned
			during a game,
			as indicated by the #trait# on its base and indicated
			on its
			character card.</item>
        <item>TRANSPORTER\n
			A character using the Carry ability and Move and
			Attack ability
			usually indicated by the #transSpeed#, #transFlight#,
			or the
			#transSwim# speed symbol.</item>
		<item>ULTRA-HEAVY OBJECT\nAn object that can only be carried
			by characters with a point value of 100 points or more. Ultra-
			Heavy objects modify a character’s damage value by +3 when
			used in a close combat attack; they may not be used in a
			ranged combat attack or placed with Telekinesis. Ultra Heavy
			object tokens have a purple border and are only destroyed if
			they are dealt 4 or more damage.</item>
        <item>UNAVOIDABLE DAMAGE\n
			Damage dealt that can’t be evaded, reduced,
			modified, ignored, or
			transferred to a different character.</item>
        <item>UNIQUE\n
			A character rank represented by a silver, bronze, or
			gold ring
			around the outer edge of a character’s base. Only one copy
			of a
			particular Unique character can be added to a given force.
			</item>
        <item>UNMODIFIED\n
			A character’s base combat value, unaffected by any
			modifiers such
			as those from powers, terrain, and so on.</item>
		<item>UNOCCUPIED SQUARE\nA square on the battlefield that does
			not have a character in it. Terrain effects would not cause a
			square to be considered occupied.</item>
        <item>USE\n
			To employ a power, ability, or effect.</item>
        <item>VICTORY CONDITIONS\n
			The rules that outline how a winner is
			determined at the end of a
			HeroClix game.</item>
        <item>WATER TERRAIN\n
			Squares inside a blue boundary line are water
			terrain.</item>
        <item>WILD CARD\n
			A team ability that allows a character to use any
			team ability
			possessed by any friendly character on the map.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>