<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="objects">
        <item>OBJECTS\nObjects are either light (yellow-ringed object tokens),
    heavy (red-ringed object tokens), or immobile (blue-ringed object
    tokens). Objects without special effects are called standard objects
    and follow all rules in this section normally. Special Objects follow
    normal object rules but also have special effects that can impact
    nearby terrain and characters, or characters that hold
    them.\n\nOBJECTS
    IN YOUR FORCE\n
    You may bring up to three objects as
    part of your force
    to a game. The
    first two objects added to your force
    must be different
    types (heavy,
    light, or immobile), and the third
    object can be any
    type, though you
    must have at least one heavy and one
    light among your
    three objects.
    Any or all of these objects may be
    special objects, but
    each special
    object must not have the same name as
    any other special
    object on
    your force.
    Standard objects cost 0 points
    to add to your
    force, but special objects may
    have a point value listed
    on their
    associated card, and cost that
    many
    points to add to your
    force.\n\nPLACING OBJECTS\n
    Between Steps 2 and 3 in the “Preparing
    For
    Battle” section (see p. 5), players can place
    objects. Starting
    with
    the first player, each player
    takes turns placing one of their
    objects. Objects
    must be placed in clear terrain outside of any
    player’s starting area. Special objects must also be
    placed 5 or more
    squares away from any player’s
    starting area.\n\n
    OBJECTS AS TERRAIN\n
    A
    square containing an object not held by a
    character is hindering
    terrain.\n\nIMMOBILE OBJECTS\n
    Immobile objects can’t be picked up,
    moved
    or
    placed using any game effect.</item>
        <item>DESTROYING OBJECTS\nObjects can be destroyed using the rules for
    destroying a square of blocking terrain (see p. 13).
    A character in
    the same square as an object does
    not take damage when the object is
    destroyed.
    An attacker can’t target both a character and an
    object with
    the same attack. A destroyed object
    is removed from the game and does
    not cause a
    debris marker to be placed.</item>
        <item>SPECIAL OBJECTS
    Special objects are objects (either tokens or
    3-D
    objects) marked with the symbol. They
    represent items on the
    battlefield that create
    special effects or grant characters holding or
    using
    them special abilities. Regardless of which player
    places a
    special object, any player can use its
    abilities, and all players are
    subject to its effects.
    The abilities of the special object continue
    whether
    the object is being held or occupying a square,
    though some
    objects may specify that their effects
    are ignored when they are held.</item>
        <item>USING OBJECTS AS WEAPONS\n
    Some powers and abilities (such as
    Super
    Strength) allow a character to pick up and hold an
    object, and
    then use it in close combat and ranged
    combat attacks. An object is
    removed from the
    game once it is used in an attack, even if the attack
    fails or is evaded.</item>
        <item>PICKING UP AN OBJECT\n
    While a character using
    Super Strength is
    moving
    due to its own action, it can pick up an
    object. The
    object must
    be in either a square the character
    occupies or
    a square adjacent to
    one the character
    moves through. A character can
    pick up an object
    even
    if another character occupies the same square
    as the object.
    Immediately place the object token
    someplace that
    indicates the
    character using Super
    Strength is holding the object. If
    entering that
    square
    requires that the character end its movement, it
    cannot pick up
    an object
    adjacent to that square
    (the object must be in
    either a square
    the character
    occupies or in an adjacent square). If a
    character
    is not
    holding an object and is given an action that
    requires the character
    to not be holding an object
    during that action,
    then the character
    cannot pick up
    an object during that
    action.</item>
        <item>HOLDING AN OBJECT\n
    A character can hold only one object at
    a
    time.
    A character can’t drop an object once it is held.
    An object held
    by a character can’t normally
    be targeted, destroyed, or taken away
    from the
    holding character. To dispose of a held object, the
    character
    must use it in an attack. If, however, a
    character holding an object
    is defeated or loses
    the ability to use Super Strength, the character
    automatically drops the object, which stays in
    the square the
    character occupied when it was
    defeated or the power was lost. If
    there is already
    an object in the square when an object is dropped,
    the dropped object is removed from the game.</item>
        <item>THE INFINITY GAUNTLET\n
    Cost: Infinity Gauntlet costs 10 points, plus 5 points for each Gem attached to it. At least one Gem must be attached to the gauntlet to activate it. You can\'t attach more than one of the same type of Gem. (15-40)\n
    \n
    Assign: Infinity Gauntlet is assigned to a character when you reveal your force and only that character can use its effects. When assigned character is KO\'d, opponent scores the Infinity Gauntlet. \n
    \n
    Setup: Infinity Gauntlet dial begins on the green line, but does not have a KO click; the dial may rotate past the starting line. You can not add special objects to your force if Infinity Gauntlet is part of it. \n
    \n
    Turning the Dial: At the end of your turn, if assigned character was given a non-free action this turn, choose one: 1) deal assigned character 1 unavoidable damage; or 2) roll a d6 that can\'t be rerolled and turn the Infinity Gauntlet dial to the right that many times; or 3) if Infinity Gauntlet dial has a special power visible, you may choose to do nothing.\n
    \n
    Using Effects: When a Gem, a standard power or a special power is revealed on the dial, assigned character can use the effects associated with that if they can\'t already. You may only use the Gem effects if that Gem is attached. \n
    \n
    #soulgem# Soul Gem: Character can use Steal Energy. When character KO\'s an opposing character, heal character of 2 damage. \n
    #powergem# Power Gem: If character\'s printed range value is 4 or less, character can use Close Combat Expert. If character\'s printed range value is 5 or more, character can use Ranged Combat Expert. \n
    #timegem# Time Gem: Character can use Incapacitate and Super Senses.\n
    #spacegem# Space Gem: Character can use Phasing/Teleport and the Carry ability. Modify character\'s speed value by +2.\n
    #realitygem# Reality Gem: Character can use Probability Control, but only during character\'s turn. \n
    #mindgem# Mind Gem: Character can use Mind Control and Telekinesis.\n
    #trait#The Gauntlet Complete: If all six Gems are attached, character\'s powers and combat abilities can\'t be countered and character can use Willpower. \n
    #fancy1# Beyond Mortal Limits: At the beginning of your turn, choose an attached gem that you did not choose during your last turn. Character can use the effects of that gem until the beginning of your next turn as long as this power is showing. \n
    #fancy2# Apotheosis Approaching: Modify character\'s combat values by +1. At the beginning of your turn, choose a standard power character can\'t already use. Character can use that power until your next turn. \n
    #fancy3# Ultimate Godhood Attained: Modify character\'s combat values by +2 and character can use the effects of every attached gem. At the beginning of your turn, choose a standard power character can\'t already use. Character can use that power until your next turn. </item>
        <item>USING OBJECTS IN CLOSE COMBAT ATTACKS\n
    A character holding an
    object and making a close
    combat attack against a single character
    must use
    the object in the attack,
    unless the
    character is using a power
    that will deal
    no damage. If a character is
    using a light object in a
    close combat attack, modify the character’s
    Damage
    Value by +1 for the
    attack; if using a heavy object;
    modify the
    character’s Damage Value by
    +2 for the
    attack; if using a ultra-heavy object; modify the character\'s Damage Value by +3 for the attack;.</item>
        <item>USING OBJECTS IN RANGED COMBAT ATTACKS\n
    A
    character holding an
    object may throw it at a
    single
    opposing
    character;
    a character holding
    an
    object does not have to
    attack with
    the object when given a ranged
    combat
    action. To throw an object, give
    the character a
    ranged combat
    action and make a ranged combat
    attack,
    even if its range value is 0.
    Regardless of the
    attacker’s Range Value,
    light objects can be thrown
    8
    squares; heavy objects, 6 squares; ultra-heavy objects, can\'t be thrown.
    Regardless of
    the attacker’s
    Damage
    Value, a successful ranged
    combat
    attack with an object deals
    Object
    Damage.
    Object Damage means a light
    object deals 2
    damage; and a
    heavy
    object deals 3 damage.</item>
        <item>UTILITY BELT\n
    Cost: Utility Belt costs 7 points, plus 1 point if the Costume slot is
    active, plus 1 point for each Utility Belt Item slot that will be active
    this game (other slots are inactive). At least one Utility Belt Item
    slot must be active.(8-14)\n
    Assign: Utility Belt is assigned to a character when you build your
    force and only that character can use its effects. When the assigned
    character is KO\'d, opponent scores Utility Belt.\n
    Setup: Utility Belt begins the game on the green line. After forces
    are revealed, attach up to one Utility Belt Costume #sos#
    if the
    Costume slot is active and as many Utility Belt Items #utilityBelt#
    as
    there are active slots (no more than three of any specific Utility
    Belt Item). The Utility Belt has no KO click and may rotate past the
    starting line.\n
    Turning the Dial: At the end of your turn, if the assigned character
    was given a non-free action, roll a d6 that can\'t be rerolled and
    turn the Utility Belt to the right that many times. If a special power
    is revealed while turning the dial, immediately stop turning the
    dial.\n
    Using Effects: All Costumes and Items grant the character powers
    and abilities that can be used as directed by their Resource Cards.
    Once a Utility Belt Item has been used, it is removed from the
    Utility Belt.\n
    #trait# Battle Plan: If three or more Utility Belt Items are attached,
    assigned character can use Indomitable. If five or more Utility Belt
    Items are attached, you may give the assigned character a free
    action and select an opposing character within 10 squares and line
    of fire; that opposing character can\'t use team abilities until the
    beginning of your next turn.\n
    #fancy1# Prep Time: Give the assigned character a double power action
    and turn the Utility Belt to any click that does not have a special
    power. Do not otherwise turn the dial at the end of your turn.\n
    #fancy2# Shared Resources: Give the assigned character a power action.
    Remove a Utility Belt Item from the Utility Belt and place it in an
    adjacent square. Flip that item\'s Resource Card; that item is now a
    Relic assigned to your force.\n
    #fancy3# Hidden Cache: At the beginning of your turn, you may activate
    an inactive slot. In addition, you may replace or attach any one
    Utility Belt Item or Costume to the Utility Belt. At the end of the
    turn, roll a d6 to turn the dial as described above even if the
    character does not take a non-free action.\n
    #fancy4# Quick Swap: Give the assigned character a power action and
    replace any number of attached Utility Belt Items with different
    Utility Belt Items.\n
    #utilityBelt#: When a number is revealed, if a Utility Belt Item in that
    slot is used this turn, it is not removed from the Utility Belt.\n
    #paraBox#: When a number is revealed, if that slot is active but empty, at
    the beginning of your turn, you may attach any Utility Belt Item to
    this slot.\n
    x2: When numbers are revealed, if the character uses a Utility
    Belt Item in one of the indicated slots, it may use an Item in the
    other slot as a free action as long as the two items are not the same. Alternatively, a power and a modifier may be revealed; the
    character can use the power showing and modifies all of its
    combat values by the amount displayed.\n
    Availability: No Man\’s Land #R100</item>
        <item>UTILITY BELT ATTACHMENTS\n
    #utilityBelt# BATARANGS: Give this character a ranged combat
    action to use Incapacitate to target all opposing characters within
    6 squares and line of fire; this character can use #imptar# #chara# 
    for this
    attack. You may give this character an additional action token and
    if you do, hit characters are given an additional action token.\n
    Availability: No Man\'s Land #R102\n
    #utilityBelt# GAS PELLETS/SMOKE GRENADE: Give this
    character a power action to use Smoke Cloud until your next turn
    as a free action. When the hindering terrain markers are removed,
    deal 1 penetrating damage to each opposing character occupying
    or adjacent to any of the removed hindering terrain markers.\n
    Availability: No Man\'s Land #R101\n
    #utilityBelt# RADAR MONITOR: Give this character a power action
    and choose an opposing team ability (even if it is Uncopyable).
    This character possesses the chosen team ability for the rest of the
    game.\n
    Availability: Streets of Gotham #R102\n
    #utilityBelt# SONIC TRANSMITTER: Character can be given a
    double power action and each Flock of Bats may be given a move
    action and a close combat action, each as a free action.\n
    Availability: Batman #R102\n
    #sos# SUIT OF SORROWS: This character can use Battle Fury and
    Super Strength.\n
    Availability: Batman #R101</item>
        <item>AERIAL BAFFLER\n
    Light: Any character with the #flight# or
    #transFlight# speed mode that
    is 3 or fewer squares from this object
    gains Earthbound. Any
    character it carries takes no damage and is
    placed in the
    nearest square it can occupy. This object has no effect
    when
    held.</item>
        <item>BAT SIGNAL\n
    Cost: 2\n
    Heavy: Give a character adjacent to this object a power action 
    and choose another friendly character that is not within 8 squares of 
    this object. Place the chosen character adjacent to this character 
    and this object.</item>
        <item>BATARANGS
    Cost: 10\n
    Relic: 4-6\n
    Character can use Incapacitate, the Sharpshooter ability and 
    possesses one additional #lighting#.</item>
        <item>BATMAN COWL\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Relic: 4-6\n
    This character possesses the Batman symbol. If character already possesses the Batman symbol
    and is adjacent to a wall or square of a higher elevated terrain, 
    lines of fire drawn to it are blocked when it is not your turn.</item>
        <item>BLACK LANTERN\n
    Light: During your turn, whenever an
    opposing character within 4
    squares of this object is KOd, you may
    heal 1 damage on a single
    friendly character within 4 squares of this
    object.</item>
        <item>BLUE LANTERN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4
    squares
    of this object that can use
    Barrier or Telekinesis modify their
    range
    values by +2 and can use
    Telekinesis for 10 squares instead of 8
    (for
    all limitations of
    Telekinesis) if they can already use
    Telekinesis.</item>
        <item>BOOKCASE\n
    Light: Increase the attacker’s attack value
    by 1 when used in an
    attack.</item>
        <item>BROKEN DRONE\n
    Light: While a character is holding
    this
    object, you may choose
    to either (1) use this object normally in
    an
    attack, or (2) give this
    character a ranged combat action (treating
    the character’s range
    value as 4) and make a ranged combat attack
    against a single target
    opposing character. An attack using option 2
    deals 1 damage but does
    not destroy this object.</item>
        <item>BUCKET OF WATER\n
    Light: When not held, a square containing
    this
    object is not considered
    hindering terrain because of this object,
    it
    is considered water
    terrain instead.</item>
        <item>CAPTAIN AMERICA\'S SHIELD\n
    Light: Continual.</item>
        <item>COM DISH\n
    Heavy: When this object is used in an
    attack,
    modify the
    attacker’s damage value by +1 for the attack.</item>
        <item>COMPUTER\n
    Heavy: Increases the attacker’s attack
    value
    by 1 when used in
    an attack.</item>
        <item>COSMIC CUBE\nCost: 12\nRelic: 4-6.\n
    Immobile: Character can use Perplex and Probability Control. Each time a character uses one of these powers, after actions resolve, roll a d6 that can’t be rerolled. On a roll of 1-2, place the Cosmic Cube in the square that character occupies.</item>
        <item>CRATE\n
    Light: A character may throw this object 10
    squares.</item>
        <item>CRIMSON GEM OF CYTTORAK\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Immobile: This object can’t be
    destroyed.
    Once per game per
    character, give a
    character occupying this
    square a
    power action and
    roll a d6 that
    can’t be rerolled. On a roll
    of
    5 or
    6, place this object
    on that
    character’s card. Modify that
    character’s
    damage value by +1 and
    that
    character can use Charge, Super
    Strength,
    and Toughness.
    (Characters
    can’t use more than one damage
    reduction
    power.) When that
    character
    is defeated, place this object in
    the
    square they last
    occupied. At
    the end of the game, if an opponent’s
    character has this
    object on
    their card or all of your characters have
    been defeated, your
    opponent scores this object.</item>
        <item>DARK CAULDRON\n
    Immobile: Characters 4 or fewer squares from this
    object can’t be healed.</item>
        <item>DR. OCTOPUS ARMS\n
    Cost: 8\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    A character with Dr. Octopus Arms on its character card has a
    minimum range value of 4, has #lightning# #lightning# #lightning#, and can
    use Perplex twice during your turn, but only to target itself.</item>
        <item>DUMPSTER\n
    Heavy: This object is not destroyed when used in an
    attack. The attacker
    places it in any square adjacent to the target
    after use.</item>
        <item>DYNAMOSTAT\n
    Heavy: This object is considered to be blocking
    terrain until it is
    destroyed, but it may be picked up and moved
    normally.</item>
        <item>ELEHA\'AL VINE\n
    Light: Give a character occupying the same
    square
    as this object a power
    action. Roll a d6 and subtract 4 from the
    result, minimum result 1.
    Heal the character of damage equal to the
    result.</item>
        <item>FLASH GRENADE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Relic: 4-6\n
    Character can use the Throw a Grenade ability using Flashbang 
    Grenades and has a Grenade Pool: +3</item>
        <item>FOOM FINGER\n
    Heavy: Continual.</item>
        <item>FORCE FIELD GENERATOR\n
    Immobile: This object allows an adjacent
    character to use Barrier as if the
    character had a range value of 0.
    If this object is destroyed, any
    barrier terrain markers placed using
    Barrier granted by this object
    are removed from the game. This object
    has no effect when held.</item>
        <item>FUEL TANK\n
    Heavy: A character may throw this object
    up
    to 6 squares. If
    this object is used as part of a successful attack,
    also deal 1
    damage to all figures adjacent to the target.</item>
        <item>Gamma Bomb\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Immobile. The Gamma Bomb can\'t be destroyed and begins on the green starting line. At the beginning of each player\'s turn, if it\'s not disarmed, click the dial once to the right. Once per game per character, a character occupying this square can be given a free action to roll a d6. On a result of 4 or 5, click the dial 4 clicks to the left (12 is the maximum), and on a result of 6, disarm it. When the red line is crossed, deal 3 damage to each character and destroy each object, wall, and square of blocking terrain within 8 squares and then remove this object from the map.</item>
        <item>GAS PELLETS/SMOKE GRENADE\n
    Cost: 3\n
    Relic: 4–6\n
    Immobile: Character can use Smoke Cloud. When it does, after
    actions resolve it can be given a move action as a free action with a
    speed value of 4.</item>
        <item>GENERATOR\n
    Heavy: This object is not destroyed when
    used in an attack.
    After the Generator is used as part of an attack,
    the attacker places
    it in any square adjacent to the target after the
    attack resolves.</item>
        <item>Globe of Ultimate Knowledge\n
    Relic 6.\n
    Immobile: Character can use Outwit.\n</item>
        <item>GREEN KRYPTONITE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Characters within 4 squares modify their attack values by -1 and
    can\'t use the Flight ability Characters within 4 squares that possess
    the Superman Ally team ability or the Kryptonian keyword can\'t
    have damage dealt to them reduced below 1.\n
    Availability: Superman S101</item>
        <item>GOLD KRYPTONITE\nCost: 5\n
    Characters within 4 squares can\'t use Exploit Weakness,
    Penetrating/Psychic Blast, Pulse Wave, or Telekinesis. A character
    holding this object can\'t use any powers except Super Strength.\n
    Availability: Superman S104</item>
        <item>GRAPNEL GUN\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Relic: 4-6\n
    Character can use #impmov# #ignbt# and the Carry ability.</item>
        <item>GREEN LANTERN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4
    squares of this object that can use
    Indomitable or Willpower modify
    their defense values by +3 when they
    are the target of an attack using
    Incapacitate or Mind Control.</item>
        <item>HANDCUFFS\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Relic: 4-6\n
    Character can use Plasticity. Opposing characters adjacent to this
    character modify their attack values by -1.</item>
        <item>HARVEST STAFF\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Relic: 6\n
    This character can use Incapcitate and Outwit. When you use
    Outwit and actions resolve, if this character targets the same
    opposing character with Incapacitate, modify this character’s attack 
    value by +1. Give this character a power action and choose a 
    power; that power is countered on all opposing characters within 5 
    squares. Give this character a double power action and choose a 
    character within 10 squares and line of fire; deal that character 1 
    unavoidable damage and all of its powers and abilities are 
    countered until your next turn.</item>
        <item>INDIGO LANTERN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4
    squares of this object that can use
    Support or Regeneration only
    subtract 1 from their die roll instead
    of 2 when using those powers.</item>
        <item>IRON MAN BRIEFCASE ARMOR\n
    Cost: 12\n
    Relic: 5-6.\n
    Immobile: This character can use Force Blast and Invulnerability.</item>
        <item>JEWEL KRYPTONITE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4 squares can use Mind Control and Smoke
    Cloud if they can\'t already. Characters using Mind Control in this
    way can only target characters of a lower Cost. All characters
    within 4 squares using Mind Control and Smoke Cloud have a
    minimum range value of 6 when using those powers.\n
    Availability: Superman S103</item>
        <item>KINETIC ABSORBER\n
    Light: All clear and water terrain 2 or fewer
    squares from this object is
    hindering terrain for movement purposes.
    This object has no effect when held.</item>
        <item>KINETIC ACCELERATOR\n
    Immobile: When a character occupying the
    same
    square as this object is given a
    move or power action, roll a d6
    and
    replace the character\'s speed
    value with its speed value plus the
    result; on a result of 5 or 6,
    remove this object from the game after
    the action resolves. If the
    roll does not allow the given action to be
    performed against any
    targets, the action ends immediately. This
    object is not considered
    hindering terrain for movement purposes.</item>
        <item>KUURTH\'S HAMMER
    Cost: 8\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    This character can use Charge, #impmov# #igndmg# #ignht#, and Toughness. This 
    character modifies its attack value by +2.</item>
        <item>LASER TURRET\n
    Heavy: (optional) Once during your turn (but not
    during another action)
    when a character friendly to you occupies this
    object\'s square, give
    this object a free action to make a ranged
    combat attack
    (#attack#8,#damage#2,#lightning#4 ) against any opposing
    figure.</item>
        <item>LIGHT POST\n
    Heavy: A target with 0 or 1 action tokens
    that is successfully
    hit with this object also receives an action
    token, which can result
    in pushing damage.</item>
        <item>MAILBOX\n
    Light: Increases the attacker\'s damage
    dealt
    by 1 when used in
    an attack.</item>
        <item>MASS-ABSORBER\n
    Light: If a character using this
    object
    as part of a close
    combat attack is 3 or fewer squares from
    blocking
    terrain, modify the
    character\'s damage value by +2 (instead
    of +1).</item>
        <item>METEORITE\n
    Heavy: When this object is used in a
    successful close combat
    attack, roll one six-sided die and subtract 2
    from the result,
    minimum result 1. add the result to the attacker\'s
    unmodified damage
    value for the attack. The damage value is locked, and the damage dealt can\'t
    otherwise be modified.</item>
        <item>MIND GEM\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Character can use Mind Control and Telekinesis.\n
    This 5 point version is only to be used when attached to the Infinity Gauntlet.</item>
        <item>MIND GEM (relic)\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Relic: 5-6
    Immobile: Character can use Mind Control and Telekinesis.</item>
        <item>MJOLNIR\n
    Relic: 6 \n
    Immobile: Modify the characters\' attack and
    damage values by +2, and
    the character can use Quake, Energy
    Explosion, and the Flight
    ability.</item>
        <item>MR. FREEZE\'S GUN
    Cost: 5\n
    Relic: 5-6.\n 
    Immobile: Character can use Barrier. When it does, it can use 
    Incapacitate as a free action targeting all opposing characters 
    adjacent to a terrain marker placed by this character.</item>
        <item>NOVA HELMET\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Relic: 5-6.\n
    Immobile: This character can use Charge and the Flight ability and possesses the Nova Corps keyword.</item>
        <item>NEWSBOT\n
    Light: When you give a character an action
    to
    attack using this
    object, it does not count toward your available
    actions for the turn.</item>
        <item>OFFICE DESK\n
    Light: When a character holding this object is attacked, you may 
    modify the holding character’s defense value by +2. If you do, the 
    object is destroyed after the attack resolves.</item>
        <item>THE ONE RING\n
    Cost: 15\n
    Owner: Frodo, Frodo and Sam, Gollum, Mr. Underhill, Ringbearer, Sauron (Owners automatically roll a 6 when rolling to pick up The One Ring.)\n
    Relic: 6\n
    Immobile: The character controlling The One Ring can use Leadership, Probability Control and Stealth. At the end of each turn of the character controlling The One Ring, roll a d6 that can\’t be rerolled. On a roll of 1, the character places The One Ring in its square and is dealt 1 unavoidable damage.</item>
        <item>OPENED HYDRANT\n
    Immobile: Clear grounded terrain 3 or fewer
    squares from this object is water
    terrain. This object has no effect
    when held.</item>
        <item>ORANGE LANTERN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: When a character uses
    Poison within 4 squares of this
    object, that character is considered
    to be adjacent to opposing
    characters up to two squares away to which
    is has a clear line of
    fire.</item>
        <item>ORCRIST\n
    Cost: 5
    Relic: 5-6.\n
    Immobile: Character can use Exploit Weakness, but only to target
    characters with the Monster keyword.</item>
        <item>POWER GEM\n
    Cost: 5\n
    If character\'s printed range value is 4 or less, character can use Close Combat Expert. If character\'s range value is 5 or more, character can use Ranged Combat Expert.
    This 5 point version is only to be used when attached to the Infinity Gauntlet.</item>
        <item>POWER GEM (relic)\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    Immobile: If character\'s printed range value is 4 or less, character can use Close Combat Expert. If character\'s printed range value is 5 or more, character can use Ranged Combat Expert.</item>
        <item>RADAR MONITOR\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Relic: 5–6\n
    Immobile: This character is a wild card, but can use opposing team
    abilities instead of friendly team abilities.</item>
        <item>REALITY GEM\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Character can use Probability Control, but only during character\'s turn.\n
    This 5 point version is only to be used when attached to the Infinity Gauntlet.</item>
        <item>REALITY GEM (relic)\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    Immobile: Character can use Probability Control, but only during character\'s turn. </item>
        <item>REBREATHER\n
    Cost: 6\n
    Relic: 4-6\n
    When this character occupies water terrain, it can use Willpower.
    This character ignores opposing characters’ Poison.</item>
        <item>RED KRYPTONITE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4 squares must roll a d6 immediately before they
    are given a non-free action. On a roll of 1-2, the character is given an action token and cannot be given any non-free actions this turn, but can use Perplex until your
    next turn if they can\'t already use it.\n
    Availability: Superman S102</item>
        <item>RED LANTERN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4
    squares
    of this object that can use
    Battle Fury modify their damage
    value by
    +1.</item>
        <item>ROBIN UNIFORM\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Relic: 4-6\n
    This character possesses Teen Titans symbol. If this character already has the Teen Titans symbol, it can use the team ability as a free action.</item>
        <item>SATELLITE\n
    Light: Give a character holding this
    object
    a power action.
    Remove this object from the game and place a
    debris
    token in the
    square occupied by the character and in any two
    adjacent,
    unoccupied
    squares.</item>
        <item>SCORPIO KEY\n
    Cost: 4\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    Immobile. Modify the
    character\'s range value by +2 and that character can use
    Penetrating/Psychic Blast. When the character is defeated,
    place this
    object in the square that character last occupied.</item>
        <item>SEPARATION FIELD GENERATOR\n
    Immobile: A character holding an
    object or
    carrying a character immediately drops it into an adjacent
    square when 3 or fewer squares from this object. The
    carrying or
    holding character may continue its move. Objects
    can not be picked up
    by characters that are 3 or fewer
    squares from this object.</item>
        <item>SHIELD DISRUPTOR\n
    Light: Damage dealt to characters 4 or fewer
    squares from this object can\'t
    be reduced. This object has no effect
    when
    held.</item>
        <item>SKADI\'S HAMMER\n
    Cost: 8\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    This character can use Charge, Exploit Weakness, and Toughness.
    This character modifies its attack value by +2.</item>
        <item>SILVER MJOLNIR\n
    Heavy: Continual.</item>
        <item>SODA MACHINE\n
    Heavy: Increase the attacker\'s damage
    dealt by 1 when used in an
    attack.</item>
        <item>SONIC TRANSMITTER\n
    Cost: 7\n
    Relic: 4-6.\n
    Immobile: Give this character a power action. Each friendly Flock
    of Bats may be given a move action as a free action; halve its speed
    value for the action.</item>
        <item>SOUL GEM\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Character can use Steal Energy. When character KO\'s an opposing character, heal character of 2 damage.\n
    This 5 point version is only to be used when attached to the Infinity Gauntlet.</item>
        <item>SOUL GEM (relic)\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    Immobile: Character can use Steal Energy. When character KO\'s an opposing character, heal character of 2 damage.</item>
        <item>SPACE GEM\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Character can use Phasing/Teleport and the Carry ability. Modify character\'s speed value by +2.\n
    This 5 point version is only to be used when attached to the Infinity Gauntlet.</item>
        <item>SPACE GEM (relic)\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    Immobile: Character can use Phasing/Teleport and the Carry ability. Modify character\'s speed value by +2. </item>
        <item>STATUE\n
    Light: This object deals 3 damage when thrown
    as part of an
    attack targeting terrain or a wall.</item>
        <item>STEPLADDER\n
    Light: When this object occupies a square adjacent
    to a
    square of higher elevation, the squares
    are
    connected by a ladder.
    This object is not hindering terrain for
    movement purposes.</item>
        <item>STING\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Relic: 5-6.\n
    Immobile: Character can use Blades/Claws/Fangs. When it is given
    a close combat action, it may modify its attack value by +2; if it
    does and hits, it must roll for Blades/Claws/Fangs and the result is a
    maximum of 3.</item>
        <item>STRUCTURAL INTEGRITY FIELD\n
    Heavy: Blocking terrain (but not
    blocking terrain markers) and walls 6 or
    fewer squares from this
    object can\'t be destroyed. This object has no effect when
    held.</item>
        <item>SUIT OF SORROWS\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Relic: 4-6.\n
    Immobile: This character can use Battle Fury and Super Strength.</item>
        <item>TANK TURRET
    Cost: 2\n
    Ultra Heavy: When used in a close combat attack, modify the attacker’s damage value by +3 instead of +2. This object can’t be thrown.
    Characters less than 100 points can’t hold this object. This object can’t be the target of Telekinesis.
    This object can’t be destroyed by an attack targeting it for 3 damage; it requires 4 or more.\n
    Availability: Chaos War S102</item>
        <item>TELEPHONE BOOTH\n
    Light: Once per turn per character, a character
    occupying the same square
    as this object can be dealt 1 unavoidable
    damage as a free action. This object has no effect when
    held.</item>
        <item>TELEPORT PAD\n
    Immobile: (optional) If a character friendly to
    you
    is adjacent to this
    object, give the character a power action and
    move
    it up to 6
    squares, ignoring characters and terrain features for
    movement
    purposes.</item>
        <item>TIME GEM\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Character can use Incapacitate and Super Senses.\n
    This 5 point version is only to be used when attached to the Infinity Gauntlet.</item>
        <item>TIME GEM (relic)\n
    Cost: 10\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    Immobile: Character can use Incapacitate and Super Senses.</item>
        <item>TOMBSTONE\n
    Heavy: The defense value of a character
    holding a Tombstone is
    modified by +2. After the resolution of an
    unsuccessful attack
    against a character holding a Tombstone, remove
    Tombstone from the
    game.</item>
        <item>TRAPPED DUMPSTER\n
    Heavy: When this object is picked
    up,
    roll a d6. On a result of
    1, deal the character that picked up this
    object 1 damage immediately
    after the action resolves (even if the
    character no longer holds the
    object).</item>
        <item>VIOLET LANTERN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4
    squares of this object that can use
    Mind Control modify their range
    value for that attack by +2 (figures
    with a range of 0 replace their
    range with 6 instead of 4 for that
    attack), and if that attack is
    successful, each character
    successfully hit modifies its damage value
    by +1 until its free
    action granted by Mind Control is resolved.</item>
        <item>WHITE KRYPTONITE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Other squares within 4 squares become clear terrain instead of
    hindering terrain. This has no effect on objects or water terrain.\n
    Availability: Superman S105</item>
        <item>WHITE LANTERN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Immobile: Characters within 4 squares of
    this object that can use Support or
    Regeneration can\'t have those
    powers, or special powers that allow
    their use, countered.</item>
        <item>WONDER GIRL LASSO\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Relic: 5-6\n
    This character can use Steal Energy, but is also healed when its
    ranged combat attack causes an opposing character to take damage.</item>
        <item>X-KRYPTONITE\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4 squares that are 75 points or less can use the
    Flight ability for as long as they are within 4 squares.\n
    Availability: Superman S106</item>
        <item>YELLOW LANTERN\n
    Cost: 5\n
    Light: Characters within 4
    squares of this object
    that can use Exploit Weakness or
    Penetrating/Psychic Blast
    modify their attack value by +1.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

</resources>