<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

  <string-array name="speed_abilities_names">
    <item>FLURRY</item>
    <item>LEAP/CLIMB</item>
    <item>PHASING/TELEPORT</item>
    <item>EARTHBOUND/NEUTRALIZED</item>
    <item>CHARGE</item>
    <item>MIND CONTROL</item>
    <item>PLASTICITY</item>
    <item>FORCE BLAST</item>
    <item>SIDESTEP</item>
    <item>HYPERSONIC SPEED</item>
    <item>STEALTH</item>
    <item>RUNNING SHOT</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="speed_abilities">
    <item>FLURRY\nGive this character a close combat action. After the close combat attack 
    resolves, it may make a second close combat attack as a free action.</item>
    <item>LEAP/CLIMB\nGive this character a move action and move it up to its speed value; 
    during this movement, this character adds 2 to its d6 roll when breaking away and can use 
    #impmov#, #ignet#, #ignht#, #ignobt#, #doubleoarr#. 
    When you give this character a close
    combat action, it may target a character regardless of the target’s elevation.</item>
    <item>PHASING/TELEPORT\nGive this character a move action and move it
    up
    to its speed value; this character can use #impmov#, #ignet#, #ignht#, #ignbt#, #chara# during this movement.</item>
    <item>EARTHBOUND/NEUTRALIZED\nThis character possesses #speed#, #attack#, #defense#, #damage# instead
    of its combat symbols. This power can’t be countered or ignored.</item>
    <item>CHARGE\nGive this character a power action; halve its speed
    value for the action.
    Move this character up to its speed value and
    then it may be given a
    close combat
    action as a free action. A
    character using this power ignores knock back.</item>
    <item>MIND CONTROL\nGive this character a close or ranged combat action (minimum
    range value 4) that deals no damage. A successfully hit target becomes friendly to
    your force. Each target hit may be assigned one action as a free action, immediately
    after which the target becomes an opposing character again. Deal this character 1
    unavoidable damage if the successfully hit targets’ combined point value is 150 points
    or more.
    </item>
    <item>PLASTICITY\nThis character adds 2 to its d6 roll when breaking away. Opposing
    characters can’t automatically break away from this character and subtract 2 from
    their d6 roll when breaking away from this character. Opposing characters entering a
    square adjacent to this character must end their movement, even if they would not
    have to do so normally.</item>
    <item>FORCE BLAST\nGive this character a power action and roll a d6; a single adjacent 
    opposing character is knocked back from this character a number of squares equal to 
    the result. When this character hits with an attack, you may choose that it generates 
    knock back if it doesn’t already. 
    </item>
    <item>SIDESTEP\nGive this character a free action; it can move with a locked speed 
    value of 2.</item>
    <item>HYPERSONIC SPEED\nGive this character a power action and move it up to 
    its speed value. It adds 2 to its d6 roll when breaking away and can use 
    #impmov# #doubleo#.
    During its move, this character may, as a free action, make one close combat or ranged 
    combat attack with its range value halved for the attack. This character must be in a 
    square where it could legally end its move in order to make the attack. 
    </item>
    <item>STEALTH\nWhen it is not your turn, hindered lines of fire drawn
    to this character
    are blocked.</item>
    <item>RUNNING SHOT\nGive this character a power action; halve its
    speed value for
    the action. Move this character up to its speed value
    and it may be
    given a ranged
    combat action as a free action.</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="attack_abilities_names">
    <item>BLADES/CLAWS/FANGS</item>
    <item>ENERGY EXPLOSION</item>
    <item>PULSE WAVE</item>
    <item>QUAKE</item>
    <item>SUPER STRENGTH</item>
    <item>INCAPACITATE</item>
    <item>PENETRATING/PSYCHIC BLAST</item>
    <item>SMOKE CLOUD</item>
    <item>PRECISION STRIKE</item>
    <item>POISON</item>
    <item>STEAL ENERGY</item>
    <item>TELEKINESIS</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="attack_abilities">
    <item>BLADES/CLAWS/FANGS\nWhen this character is given a close combat
    action, you
    may roll a d6 after making a successful attack roll. The
    result replaces
    this character’s
    damage value, then that damage value
    is locked.</item>
    <item>ENERGY EXPLOSION\nWhen this character is given a ranged combat action
    and deals damage, an area of effect may include all untargeted characters that are
    adjacent to one or more hit targets. Hit targets are dealt damage normally, other
    hit characters are dealt 1 damage for each #lightning#
    printed on this character’s base.
    </item>
    <item>PULSE WAVE\nGive this character a ranged combat action even if it is adjacent
    to an opposing character; the area of effect for this attack is half the character’s
    range. Draw lines of fire to all other characters within the area of effect, including
    at least one opposing character; these lines of fire ignore all game effects except
    for walls, blocking and elevated terrain. Game effects possessed or used by
    characters with a line of fire drawn to them are ignored until the action has been
    resolved. If a line of fire is drawn to more than 1 character, this character’s damage
    value becomes 1 and is locked. Each character hit is dealt damage.
    </item>
    <item>QUAKE\nGive this character a close combat action; this character’s damage value
    becomes 2 and is locked. Make a close combat attack that targets all opposing
    characters this character can attack with a close combat attack. Each hit character is
    knocked back 2 squares.</item>
    <item>SUPER STRENGTH\nWhen this character moves due to its own action, it may 
    either pick up an object or place an object it is holding. The object must be picked up 
    from or placed in either a square the character occupies or an adjacent square. If this 
    power is lost or countered while this character is holding an object, immediately place 
    the object in the square this character occupies. 
    </item>
    <item>INCAPACITATE\nGive this character a close combat or ranged combat action to 
    make an attack that deals no damage. If the attack hits, give the target an action token; 
    if the target already has 2 action tokens, deal the target 1 penetrating damage. 
    </item>
    <item>PENETRATING/PSYCHIC BLAST\nGive this character a ranged combat
    action.
    Damage from the attack is penetrating damage.</item>
    <item>SMOKE CLOUD\nGive this character a power action; place up to 6 hindering terrain
    markers in distinct, adjacent squares that are all within this character’s range (minimum range
    value 4). At least one of the terrain markers must be within line of fire when it is placed. The
    terrain markers remain until the beginning of your next turn. Characters that occupy these
    terrain markers modify their attack value by -1 unless they can use Smoke Cloud or ignore
    hindering terrain for line of fire purposes.</item>
    <item>PRECISION STRIKE\nWhen this character makes an attack, it can’t be evaded, and the
    damage dealt can’t be reduced below 1 or transferred.</item>
    <item>POISON\nAt the beginning of your turn, give this character a
    free action and deal 1
    damage to each adjacent opposing character.</item>
    <item>STEAL ENERGY\nEach time an opposing character takes damage from
    a close combat
    attack made by this character, heal this character of 1
    damage.</item>
    <item>TELEKINESIS\nGive this character a power action and designate a
    target
    character or object (A) and a destination square (B). This
    character, A, and B
    must all be within 8 squares and line of fire of
    each other. Place A
    in B. If A is a
    character, it must be a single base
    character and possess #tiny# or #damage# the symbols.
    If A is an
    opposing
    character, make a close or ranged combat attack that deals no damage
    against A, and only place the character in B if the target is hit. If
    A is an object and
    B is occupied by an opposing character, this
    character may make a
    ranged combat
    attack against B, dealing object
    damage and destroying the object. A character that has been placed by Telekinesis this turn can’t use Telekinesis this turn.</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="defense_abilities_names">
    <item>SUPER SENSES</item>
    <item>TOUGHNESS</item>
    <item>DEFEND</item>
    <item>COMBAT REFLEXES</item>
    <item>ENERGY SHIELD/DEFLECTION</item>
    <item>BARRIER</item>
    <item>MASTERMIND</item>
    <item>WILLPOWER</item>
    <item>INVINCIBLE</item>
    <item>IMPERVIOUS</item>
    <item>REGENERATION</item>
    <item>INVULNERABILITY</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="defense_abilities">
    <item>SUPER SENSES\nWhen this character is hit by an attack, you may
    roll a d6 before
    damage is dealt. On a result of 5 or 6, this
    character evades the attack.</item>
    <item>TOUGHNESS\nDamage dealt to this character is reduced by 1.</item>
    <item>DEFEND\nAny adjacent friendly character may replace its defense
    value with this
    character’s unmodified defense value.</item>
    <item>COMBAT REFLEXES\nModify this character’s defense value by +2 against close 
    combat attacks. This character ignores knock back.
    </item>
    <item>ENERGY SHIELD/DEFLECTION\nModify this character’s defense value
    by +2
    against ranged combat attacks.</item>
    <item>BARRIER\nGive this character a power action; place up to 4 blocking terrain
    markers in distinct, adjacent squares of clear terrain that are all within this character’s
    range (minimum range value 4). At least one of the terrain markers must be within
    line of fire when it is placed. The terrain markers remain until the beginning of your
    next turn.
    </item>
    <item>MASTERMIND\nWhen this character would be dealt damage, you may
    instead
    choose to have all the damage be dealt to a single adjacent
    friendly
    character with
    a point value less than this character’s. Any
    additional effects of
    the damage dealt
    (knock back, penetrating damage,
    etc.) are applied to the character taking
    the damage.
    Damage dealt by
    this power is not an attack.</item>
    <item>WILLPOWER\nThis character may ignore pushing damage.</item>
    <item>INVINCIBLE\nHalf of damage dealt to this character is ignored.</item>
    <item>IMPERVIOUS\nWhen this character is dealt damage, roll a d6. On a
    result of 5 or 6,
    the damage dealt is reduced to 0. On a result of
    1–4, the damage dealt
    is reduced by
    2.</item>
    <item>REGENERATION\nGive this character a power action. Roll a d6 and
    subtract 2
    from the result, minimum result 0. Heal this character of
    damage equal to
    the result.</item>
    <item>INVULNERABILITY\nDamage dealt to this character is reduced by 2.</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="damage_abilities_names">
    <item>RANGED COMBAT EXPERT</item>
    <item>BATTLE FURY</item>
    <item>SUPPORT</item>
    <item>EXPLOIT WEAKNESS</item>
    <item>ENHANCEMENT</item>
    <item>PROBABILITY CONTROL</item>
    <item>SHAPE CHANGE</item>
    <item>CLOSE COMBAT EXPERT</item>
    <item>EMPOWER</item>
    <item>PERPLEX</item>
    <item>OUTWIT</item>
    <item>LEADERSHIP</item>
  </string-array>
  <string-array name="damage_abilities">
    <item>RANGED COMBAT EXPERT\nGive this character a power action. It makes a
    ranged combat attack against a single target character; before making the attack, you
    may modify its attack value by +2, its damage value by +2, or both combat values by
    +1.
    </item>
    <item>BATTLE FURY\nThis character ignores Shape Change, can’t make
    ranged combat
    attacks, can’t be targeted by Mind Control or
    Incapacitate, and can’t be
    carried.</item>
    <item>SUPPORT\nGive this character a power action and make an attack
    roll (that is not
    an attack) against an adjacent friendly character as
    though making a
    close combat
    attack. When using this power, neither
    this character nor the target can be
    adjacent
    to an opposing character;
    ignore all combat value modifiers for this
    action. If the
    attack roll
    succeeds, roll a d6 and subtract 2 from the result, minimum
    result 1.
    The
    target is healed of damage equal to the result.</item>
    <item>EXPLOIT WEAKNESS\nGive this character a close combat action.
    Damage from
    the attack is penetrating damage.</item>
    <item>ENHANCEMENT\nWhen an adjacent friendly character makes a ranged
    combat
    attack, this character modifies the adjacent friendly
    character’s damage
    value by +1.</item>
    <item>PROBABILITY CONTROL\nOnce during your turn, this character allows you to
    reroll one of your rolls, ignoring the original roll. A character using this power must be within
    range (minimum range 6) and line of fire to the character for which the original roll was
    made. Using the same rules, once per round during an opponent’s turn, this character allows
    you to force that opponent to reroll one of their rolls, ignoring the original roll.
    </item>
    <item>SHAPE CHANGE\nWhen this character is chosen as the target of an
    attack, you may
    roll a d6. On a result of 5 or 6, the attacker can’t
    target this
    character with an attack this
    turn and the attacker may
    choose another target character instead. The
    attacker then
    makes the
    attack unless there are no targets, in which case the action
    resolves
    without an
    attack.</item>
    <item>CLOSE COMBAT EXPERT\nGive this character a power action. It makes a close
    combat attack against a single opposing target character; before making the attack you may
    modify its attack value by +2, its damage value by + 2, or both combat values by +1.
    </item>
    <item>EMPOWER\nWhen an adjacent friendly character makes a close combat attack, this
    character modifies that adjacent friendly character’s damage value by +1.</item>
    <item>PERPLEX\nGive this character a free action to modify by +1 or –1 any combat value of
    a target character until the beginning of your next turn. A character using this power must
    be within range (minimum range 6) and line of fire to the target. If a target character is
    damaged or healed, the effect of Perplex on that character ends immediately.
    </item>
    <item>OUTWIT\nGive this character a free action to counter a power or a combat ability
    possessed by a single target opposing character until the beginning of your next turn.
    Any game effects with a duration specified by the countered power or combat ability
    are removed. A character using this power must be within range (minimum range 6)
    and line of fire to the target.
    </item>
    <item>LEADERSHIP\nAt the beginning of your turn, give this character a
    free action and
    roll a d6. On a result of 5–6, add one action to your
    action total for
    that turn and this
    character may remove an action
    token from an adjacent friendly character with
    a
    lower point value.</item>
  </string-array>

</resources>
